ECJTU
■
Luokun
地方法院
你做的很好 非常好
You did a wonderful job. Wonderful.
漫长复杂的审理程序已经结束
To continue, you've listened to a long and complex case,
这是一宗一级谋杀案
murder in the first degree.
预谋杀人
Premeditated murder
在刑事诉讼中是刑责最重的罪名
is the most serious charge tried in our criminal courts.
你们都已经听过证词
You've listened to the testimony,
也明了法律条文的规定
had the law interpreted as it applies in this case.
现在你们必须坐下来
It's now your duty to sit down
好好地理清这宗案子的真伪
and try and separate the facts from the fancy.
在本案中已有一人身亡
One man is dead.
另一个人的生死掌握在你们手上
Another man's life is at stake.
如果你们能提出合理的怀疑
If there's a reasonable doubt in your minds
无法确认被告是否有罪
as to the guilt of the accused...
基于这个合理的怀疑
a reasonable doubt,
你们必须做出无罪的判决
then you must bring me a verdict of not guilty.
如果你们找不出合理的怀疑
If there's no reasonable doubt,
你们必须基于良知
then you must, in good conscience...
判决被告有罪
find the accused guilty.
然而你们的决定必须一致
However you decide, your verdict must be unanimous.
如果你们裁定被告有罪
In the event that you find the accused guilty,
本庭将会对他施以严厉的惩罚
the bench will not entertain a recommendation for mercy.
最高的刑罚会是死刑
The death sentence is mandatory in this case.
这是一项沉重的责任
You are faced with a grave responsibility.
谢谢各位
Thank you, gentlemen.
后备陪审员可以离去
The alternate jurors are excused.
陪审团请退下
The jury will now retire.
十二怒汉
要来块口香糖吗?
Wanna piece of gum?
-我不要 谢谢 -这扇窗户卡住了
- No, thanks. - This thing isn't movin'.
-快来帮帮我 -好了
- I'll give you a hand. - That's it.
你知道吗? 我打电话问过气象局
You know somethin'? I called the Weather Bureau this morning.
今天将是今年中最热的一天
This is gonna be the hottest day of the year.
我还以为这里有空调
You'd think they'd air-condition this place.
先生 请问尊姓大名?
What is your name, sir?
-就是那个 -谢谢你
- Oh, it's...that one. - Thank you very much.
好了 各位 大家都到了
OK, gentlemen. Everybody's here.
如果你们需要别的东西
Now, if there's anything you want,
我就在外面 尽管叫我
I'll be right outside the door. Just knock.
我不知道他们会锁上门
I never knew they locked the door.
他们当然会锁门 你以为他们会怎么做?
Sure they lock the door. What'd you think?
我不知道 我只是从来没想过会有这种事
I don't know. It just never occurred to me.
-那是什么东西? -我还以为我们要投票表决
- What's that for? - I thought we might wanna vote by ballot.
好主意 或许我们该选他当参议员
Great idea. Maybe we can get him elected senator.
-你觉得如何? -我不知道 挺有趣的
- How'd you like it? - I don't know. It was pretty interesting.
是吗? 我差点就睡着了
Yeah? I almost fell asleep.
我从来没有当过陪审员
I mean, I've never been on a jury before.
是吗? 我有很多次的经验
No? I've sat on many juries.
律师们说的话让我很火大
Those lawyers talk and talk,
凶手是谁真的是太明显了
even when it's an open-and-shut case like this one.
你听过这么多无聊的话吗?
Ever hear so much talk about nothin'?
那是他们的工作
I guess they're entitled.
一点都没错 这就是司法系统
They're entitled. It's the system, but...
我觉得现在孩子得吃点苦头
if you ask me, I'd slap those tough kids down
才不敢惹麻烦
before they start any trouble.
这能帮我们省下时间跟金钱
It saves a lot of time and money.
-开始裁决吧 -好主意
- Let's get started. - Good idea.
大家动作快一点 我们还有很多工作要做
We've probably all got things to do here.
先等一下
We can start with a five- minute break.
还有一个人在洗手间里
One gentleman is in the bathroom.
-我们照常规坐吗? -我不知道 应该是吧
- Are...we gonna sit in order? - I don't know. I guess so.
你坐到我的位置了
Buddy, you're in my seat.
-对不起 -没关系
- Oh, excuse me. - That's all right.
这里的风景还不错吧
Hey, that's not a bad view, huh?
你对这个案子有什么看法?
What did you think of the case?
我觉得很有趣
I mean, it had a lot of interest for me.
一点都不无聊 你了解我的意思吧
No real...dead spots. You know what I mean.
能遇上谋杀案算我们运气好
We were lucky to get a murder case.
我还以为我们会遇上伤害案或窃盗案
I figured us for an assault or burglary.
那真的很无聊!
Boy, they can be the dullest!
-那是伍尔沃斯大楼吗? -没错
- Hey, is that the Woolworth Building? - That's right.
我从小到大都住在纽约 却从来没有去过那里
I've lived here all my life. I've never been inside it.
你们得抽丝剥茧地把案情弄清楚
If you had to sort out all that junk,
就跟电影上演的一样
like that thing with the movies.
对 关于凶刀又是怎么一回事呢?
Yeah. What about that business with the knife?
他们竟要我们这些成年人去相信那种胡言乱语
Asking grown-up people to believe that kind of jazz.
我早就知道事情会变成这样
You expect that. You know what we're dealing with.
你说的对
Yeah, I guess so.
你的鼻子通了 现在来看看你的眼睛吧
Well, your horn works. Now try your lights.
你感冒了吗?
You got a cold?
因为太热引起的感冒真是要人命
Hot-weather colds can kill you.
我只要一摸鼻子就会觉得很痛
I can hardly touch my nose.
我真的了解 我感冒才刚好
Sure do. I just got over one.
快点! 团长先生 要开始了
Oh, come on! Mr Foreman, let's go.
那家伙还在洗手间里
The guy's still in the bathroom.
有什么消息吗? 我还没有空看报纸
What's new? I didn't get a chance to see a paper this morning.
不知道今天的股市指数是多少
I was only wondering how the market closed.
你是做股票的?
You got a seat on the exchange?
我是股票经纪人
I'm a broker.
我开了一间传呼公司
I run a messenger service.
叫做贝克传呼公司
The Beck and Call Company.
公司名字是我太太取的
The name is my wife's idea.
我白手起家 现在雇了37个人
Got 377 men workin'. Started with nothin'.
好了 大家快坐下
OK, men. Let's take our seats.
好了 我们可以很快离开这里
We can all get out of here pretty quick.
我已经买好今晚的球赛门票
I have tickets to that ball game tonight.
是洋基队对克利夫兰队的比赛
Yanks and Cleveland.
本案的被告是摩杰路斯基
We've got this kid Modjelewski in there.
这孩子简直无药可救
He's a real bull, this kid.
他应该被关进牢里 你知道吗?
Real jug-handled. You know?
你真的很喜欢看棒球 对吧?
You're a real baseball fan, aren't ya?
我们要坐在哪里?
Where do we sit here?
我想我们得依照 陪审员的编号坐下
I thought we'd sit in order, by jury numbers.
一 二 三 以此类推 沿着桌子坐下
One, two, three and so on around the table,
希望大家别介意
if that's OK with you gentlemen.
-那有什么差别呢? -听起来挺合理的
- What's the difference? - It's reasonable to sit in order.
-就这么办吧 -十二号坐这
- Let it be. - That's twelve.
从你开始一 二
We go around one, two...
你对检察官的印象如何?
What was your impression of the prosecuting attorney?
你说什么?
I beg pardon?
我觉得他很尖锐
I thought he was really sharp,
像连珠炮似地提出问题
the way he handled all those points one by one...
但前后顺序相当有逻辑
in logical sequence.
让我留下了深刻的印象
I was very impressed.
我觉得他非常专业
I think he...he did an expert job.
也非常有冲劲
A lot of drive, too. You know? Real drive.
大伙们 请安静
OK, fellas. Can we hold it down a minute? Fellas?
我们就要开始了
Say, we'd like to get started.
站在窗户旁边的先生
Gentleman at the window.
-我们就要开始了 -对不起
- We'd like to get started. - Oh, I'm sorry.
这真的很难懂 对吧? 那孩子杀了他的父亲
The kid kills his father, just like that.
听我说 这种事常发生
Listen, it happens all the time.
养子不教父之过 或许那是他活该
They let those kids run wild up there.
-大家都到了吗? -那老头还在洗手间里
- Is everyone here? - The old man is inside.
-麻烦你去叫他过来好吗? -没问题
- Would you knock on the door for him? - Yeah.
你是洋基队的球迷吗?
Are you a Yankee fan?
不 我支持巴尔的摩队
No, Baltimore.
巴尔的摩队?
Baltimore?
那就像是每天 头都会被铁橇敲上一记
That's like being hit in the head with a crowbar once a day.
除了他们的外野手还不错之外
Who have they got?
他们有什么厉害的?
Who have they got besides good groundkeepers?
我们要开始了
Say, we'd like to get started.
对不起 我不是故意要你们等我
Forgive me, gentlemen. I didn't mean to keep you waiting.
巴尔的摩队!
Baltimore!
好了 各位 请注意听我说
OK, if I can have your attention.
你们想要怎么做都可以
You fellas can handle this thing any way you want.
我不打算制定任何规则
I'm...you know, I'm not gonna make any rules.
我们可以先进行讨论再来表决
We can, well, discuss it first, then vote on it.
那是一种可行的方法
That's, of course... that's one way.
当然啰 我们也可以立刻进行表决
And, well, we can vote on it right now.
我想依照惯例 我们得先进行假投票
I think it's customary to take a preliminary vote.
我们来投票吧 谁知道呢?
Yeah, let's vote. Who knows?
或许我们可以立刻离开这里
Maybe we can all get outta here.
好吧 大家都知道
OK. Then I think that you know that
这是一宗一级谋杀案
we have a first-degree murder charge here...
如果我们裁决被告有罪
and if we vote the accused guilty,
那等于是送他坐上电椅
we've got to send him to the chair.
-那是必然的结果 -我们知道
- That's mandatory. - I think we know that.
好了 现在来表决吧
Yeah, let's see who's where.
有人反对进行表决吗?
Anyone doesn't wanna vote?
我没意见
It's fine with me.
记住 不论如何
OK, then, just remember that
我们都得达成共识 那是规定
this has to be twelve to nothing, either way. That's the law.
大家都准备好了吗?
OK, are we ready?
认为他有罪的人请举手
All those voting guilty, please raise your hands.
一 二 三 四 五 六 七
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
八 九 十 十一
eight, nine, ten, eleven.
十一个人认为他有罪
OK, that's eleven guilty.
认为他无罪的人请举手
Those voting not guilty?
一票 好吧
One. Right.
十一票有罪 一票无罪
Eleven guilty, one not guilty.
至少现在我们有结论了
Well, now we know where we are.
天啊! 总是会出现唱反调的人
Boy, oh boy! There's always one.
我们现在该怎么办呢?
So, what do we do now?
-我猜我们得好好讨论一下 -天啊
- I guess we talk. - Boy, oh, boy.
你真的觉得他是无辜的?
You really think he's innocent?
我不知道
I don't know.
你跟我们一样坐在法庭里
You sat in court with the rest of us.
你应该可以看得出来 那孩子是个危险的杀手
You heard what we did. The kid's a dangerous killer.
他才十八岁
He's 18 years old.
他已经够大了
Well, that's old enough.
他拿刀子往他父亲的胸口戳去 把他给杀了
He stabbed his own father four inches into the chest.
在法庭上他们不断证明了这一点
They proved it a dozen different ways in court.
你要我一一跟你说明吗?
Would you like me to list 'em for you?
不必了
No.
你到底想怎么样?
Then what do you want?
我只是想谈一谈
I just want to talk.
你想谈什么?
What's there to talk about?
十一票有罪
Eleven of us think he's guilty.
除了你 大家都达成了共识
No one had to think about it twice except you.
我想问你 你真的相信他的说词?
I want to ask you something. Do you believe his story?
我不知道 或许我不相信
I don't know. Maybe I don't.
你为什么会认为他无罪?
So how come you voted not guilty?
十一个人都认为他有罪
There were eleven votes for guilty.
我真的很难举起手
It's not easy to raise my hand...
送这个孩子坐电椅
and send a boy off to die
完全不去讨论这件事
without talking about it first.
-谁说这很容易了? -没人
- Well, now, who says it's easy? - No one.
你以为我是胡乱举手的吗?
What? Just because I voted fast?
我真的觉得那孩子有罪
I honestly think the guy is guilty.
就算谈上一百年 也无法改变我的想法
Couldn't change my mind if you talked for 100 years.
我不想改变你
I'm not trying to change your mind.
但这个判决攸关一条人命
It's just that... This is somebody's life.
我们不能以5分钟就决定一个人的命运
We can't decide in five minutes.
假设我们错了呢?
Supposing we're wrong?
假设这栋房子会倒塌
Supposing this building fell on my head?
什么事都是有可能的
You can suppose anything.
一点都没错
That's right.
要花多少时间又有什么差别
What's the difference how long it takes?
或许我们花五分钟就能解决此事
Supposin' we take five minutes?
我们可以花一小时来讨论
Let's take an hour.
球赛八点才会开始
The ball game doesn't start till eight o'clock.
谁有意见?
Who's got something to say?
如果只有一小时应该没关系
I'm willing to sit for an hour.
太棒了 我已经听过所有说法
Great. I heard a good story last night...
那不是我们坐在这里的原因
That's not why we're sitting here.
好吧 请你告诉我 我们为什么要坐在这里?
All right, then you tell me. What are we sitting here for?
我不知道 或许那是没有原因的
I don't know. Maybe no reason.
这孩子老是被踢来踢去
Look, this kid's been kicked around all of his life.
他在贫民窟出生 九岁时母亲就过世了
You know, born in a slum, mother dead since he was nine.
他在孤儿院待过一年半
He lived for a year and a half in an orphanage
当时他父亲因为伪造文书罪入狱
when his father was serving a jail term for forgery.
他是先天不良
That's not a very happy beginning.
他是个充满愤怒的野孩子
He's a wild, angry kid. That's all he's ever been.
为什么?
And you know why?
因为每天都会有人打他
Cos he's been hit on the head by somebody once a day, every day.
他过了悲惨的十八年
He's had a pretty miserable 18 years.
我觉得我们该给他一个机会
I think we owe him a few words, that's all.
我要告诉你
I don't mind telling you this, mister.
我们什么都不欠他 他得到公平的审判了
We don't owe him a thing. He got a fair trial.
你觉得那场审判要花掉多少钱
What do you think that trial cost?
他有这样的机会就已经够幸运了
He's lucky he got it. Know what I mean?
听着 大家都是成年人
Look, we're all grown-ups in here.
我们都听到了实际经过 对吧?
We heard the facts, didn't we?
我们不该相信那孩子的说法
You're not gonna tell me we're supposed to believe this kid,
我们都知道他是什么样的人
knowing what he is.
我跟那样的人生活过
I've lived among them all my life.
你不能相信他们说的话 你知道的
You can't believe a word they say. You know that.
他们一生下来就是骗子
I mean, they're born liars.
只有无知的人才会相信那些话
Only an ignorant man can believe that.
-听我说 -你天生就
- Now, listen... - Do you think you were born with
相信真理吗?
a monopoly on the truth?
有足够的证据能证明他的罪行
Certain things should be pointed out to this man.
我们不需要听你训话
It's not Sunday. We don't need a sermon.
我们还有工作要做 快开始吧
We have a job to do. Now let's do it.
这是爆米花 我的公司负责推销这种产品
Rice Pops. It's a product I work on at the agency.
"天生充满活力的早餐"
"The breakfast with the built-in bounce."
这句广告词是我写的
I wrote that line.
-真的很传神 -没错
- Very catchy. - Yeah.
-请安静 -对不起
- Say, do you mind? - I'm sorry.
随手涂鸭反而能让我沉淀思绪
I have this habit of doodling. It keeps me thinking clearly.
我们还有事要做
We have work to do.
没有必要把时间耗在这里
There's no point staying here for ever.
好吧 坐在那边的先生
OK. Perhaps if the gentleman down there
不同意我们的看法
who is disagreeing with us.
如果你可以告诉我们为什么
...perhaps you could say why. Tell us what you're thinking.
或许我们能告诉你你哪里弄错了
We might be able to show you where you're mixed up.
这方法挺不错的 我并没有想太多
Maybe this is an idea. I haven't given it much thought.
似乎我们得说服他
It seems it's up to us to convince him that
他错了 我们才是对的
he's wrong and we're right.
或许我们该花几分钟的时间 好好地...
Maybe if we each took a couple of minutes just to...
那只是我的提议
Well, it was just a quick idea.
不 你的提议很棒
No, no, no. That's a good one.
我们照顺序一一发言吧
Supposing we go once around the table.
从你先来
I guess you're first.
这真的很难说出个为什么
It's hard to put into words.
我就是觉得他有罪
I just think he's guilty.
从证词来看一切非常明显
I thought it was obvious from the word go.
没有人能证明他无罪
Nobody proved otherwise.
也没有人该那么做
Nobody has to prove otherwise.
该证明他无罪的人是检察官
The burden of proof's on the prosecution.
被告不必发言
The defendant doesn't even have to open his mouth.
那是宪法规定的权利
That's in the Constitution.
我知道 但我的意思是
Sure, I know that. What I meant was...
我就是觉得他有罪
I just think he's guilty.
有目击者看到他杀人
I mean, somebody saw him do it.
好了 这就是我的想法
OK. Here's what I think.
对本案我并没有个人偏见
And I have no personal feelings about this.
我只是想讨论事实
I just wanna talk about facts.
首先
Number one.
住在凶案现场
The old man lived downstairs
楼下的那个老人
under the room where the killing took place.
在凶案发生当晚的十二点十分
At 10 minutes after 12 on the night of the killing,
他听到类似发生争执的吵闹声
he heard loud noises. Said it sounded like a fight.
他听到那个孩子大叫着 "我要杀了你"
And he heard the kid yell out "I'm gonna kill ya."
一秒钟后他听见有人摔倒的声音
A second later, he heard a body hit the floor.
于是他跑到门口
Ran to the door, opened it up,
看到那孩子冲下楼梯离开
saw the kid run down the stairs and out of the house.
他打电话报警
Called the police.
警方发现死者胸口插了一把刀
They found the old man with the knife in his chest.
法医推测死亡时间大约是午夜
The coroner fixed the time of death around midnight.
这些都是事实
Now, these are facts.
你无法反驳事实 那孩子有罪
You can't refute facts. The kid is guilty.
我跟其他人一样有同情心
I'm just as sentimental as the next fella.
我知道那孩子只有十八岁
I know he's only 18.
但他还是得付出代价
But he's still gotta pay for what he did.
我同意你的说法
I'm with you.
好了 你说完了吗?
OK. Are you finished?
-我说完了 -下一位
- Yeah. - Next.
很明显地那孩子的说词 根本都是在瞎编
It is obvious to me that the boy's entire story was flimsy.
他说案发时他在看电影
He claimed he was at the movies...
但他完全想不起来
yet he couldn't remember the names of
那部电影跟演员们的名字
the films he saw or who played in them.
-没错 -没有人看到他进出电影院
- That's right. - And no one saw him at the theatre.
住在对街的那个女人
And the woman across the street
所做出的证词呢?
if her testimony don't prove it, nothing does.
她看到他杀人
That's right. She actually saw the killing.
好了 请大家照顺序来
Fellas, please. Let's go in order.
等一下
Just a minute.
案发时这个女人 躺在床上 她睡不着
Here's a woman who's lying in bed. She can't sleep.
她热到受不了 你明白吧?
She's dyin' with the heat.
她从窗户往外看
She looks out the window,
看到那孩子 将刀子插进他父亲的胸口
and right across the street she sees the kid stick the knife into his father.
时间是十二点十分
The time is 12:10 on the nose.
完全吻合 她是看着那孩子长大的
Everything fits. She's known the kid all his life.
他家跟她家只隔了一条电车轨道
His window is opposite hers across the el tracks.
她目睹他杀人的经过
She swore she saw him do it.
当时刚好有一列电车经过
Through the windows of a passing el train.
这辆电车上没有乘客
This el train had no passengers on it.
它是要开到市区去的
It was just being moved downtown.
当时车上的灯光全暗
The lights were out
律师证明了
and they proved in court that
只要灯光是暗的 透过电车车窗
at night you can look through the windows
你可以看到另一边的景象
and see what's happening on the other side. They proved it.
我想问你一个问题
I'd like to ask you something.
你不相信那孩子
You don't believe the boy.
为什么会相信这个女人呢?
How come you believe the woman?
她跟他是一样的
She's one of "them" too, isn't she?
你以为自己很聪明 对吧?
You're a pretty smart fella, aren't ya?
各位
OK, gentlemen. Now, gentlemen.
好了 坐下吧
Come on, sit down. Sit down.
他有什么好得意的?
What's he so wise about?
好了 我们不是来吵架的
Come on. Now we're not gonna get anywhere fighting.
现在轮到谁了?
Whose turn is it next?
轮到他了 他是五号
Oh, his. Number five.
我可以弃权吗?
May I... Can I pass?
那是你的权利
Well... That's your privilege.
下一位
How about the next gentleman?
我不知道 打从一开始
Oh. Well...I don't know. I started to be convinced, you know,
我就相信他有罪
very early in the case.
我一直在寻找他的犯罪动机
You see, I was looking for a motive.
这真的很重要
That's very important because
没有犯罪动机 案子就无法成立
if you don't have a motive, where's your case, right?
住在那孩子家对面的人
Anyway, that testimony from those people
在法庭上做出的证词
across the hall from the kid's apartment...
非常有力
that was very powerful.
何况他们提到死者跟他儿子
Didn't they say something about a fight, an argument
约七点时曾发生过争吵
between the old man and his son around about seven o'clock that night?
或许我错了 但我
I could be wrong but...
-是八点才对 -没错
- It was eight o'clock, not seven. - That's right.
他们听到了争吵声
They heard an argument,
却听不清楚到底发生了什么事
couldn't hear about what.
他们听到死者 打了他儿子两下
Then they heard the father hit the boy twice.
他们看到那孩子愤怒地冲出家门
Finally they saw the boy run, angry, out of the house.
那能证明什么呢?
What does that prove?
那无法证明任何事 那只是事实的一部份
It don't prove anything. It's just part of the picture.
你说那证明了凶手有杀人动机
You said it provided a motive.
但我觉得这样的动机不够强烈
I don't think it was a very strong motive.
这孩子常常被打
This boy has been hit so many times that violence is practically...
暴力对他来说是司空见惯的事
It's a normal state of affairs with him.
我不觉得被打了两个耳光
I just can't see two slaps in the face
就足以让他气到去杀人
provoking him into committing murder.
或许他真的被逼到受不了
It may have been two too many.
每个人都有极限
Everyone has a breaking point.
你还有话要说吗?
Anything else?
-没有了 -好吧 你呢?
- No. - OK. How about you?
我不知道 话都被他们说完了
I don't know. It's all been said.
我们可以一直耗下去 结论还是一样的
You can talk here for ever. It's still the same thing.
这个孩子真的杀了人
This kid is five for 0.
看看他的记录
Well, look at his record.
他十岁就进了少年法庭
When he was 10, he was in children's court:
因为他对老师丢石头
He threw a rock at a teacher.
十五岁时进感化院
When he was 15, he was in reform school:
因为他偷了一部车子
He stole a car.
他曾因抢劫被捕
He's been arrested for muggin'.
还曾因持刀械斗被抓过两次
He was picked up twice for knife fightin'.
他的确是个用刀高手
They say he's real handy with a knife.
他的确是个好孩子
Oh, this is a very fine boy.
从五岁开始
Ever since he was five,
他老爸就会对他饱以老拳
his father beat him up regularly. He used his fists.
有那种孩子我也会那么做
So would I. A kid like that?
现在的孩子 都是那个样子
It's these kids-the way they are nowadays.
我小时候 都会叫我爸爸"父亲大人"
When I was a kid, I used to call my father "sir".
现在哪个孩子会那样叫老爸?
That's right. Ever hear a kid call his father that any more?
现在的爸爸也不在乎
Fathers don't seem to think it's important any more.
-你有孩子吗? -我有三个小孩
- You got any kids? - Three.
我有一个儿子
I got one.
他今年二十二岁了
He's 22 years old.
他九岁大时 因为打输而逃之夭夭
When he was nine years old, he ran away from a fight.
我目睹那一幕觉得丢脸丢到家了
I saw it. I was so embarrassed,
我差点没有吐出来
I almost threw up.
我说"我要让你变成一个男子汉
I said "I'm gonna make a man out of you
就算我得磨掉你的小命"
if I have to break you in two tryin'."
我的确让他变成一个男子汉
Well, I made a man out of him.
他十六岁时我们打了一架
When he was 16, we had a fight.
他打中了我的下巴 我儿子非常高大
Hit me in the jaw. He was a big kid.
我两年没有见到他
I haven't seen him for two years.
现在的孩子
Kids.
总是让父母伤透了心
You work your heart out...
我们继续吧
Well, let's get goin'.
我想我们忘了真正的重点
I think we're missing the point.
他来自破碎家庭
This boy's the product of a broken home
住在贫民窟 关于那一点我们爱莫能助
and a filthy neighbourhood. We can't help that.
我们要决定他到底有没有罪
We're here to decide his innocence or guilt,
这跟他的成长背景无关
not to go into the reasons why he grew up the way he did.
他生于贫民窟
He was born in a slum.
那是犯罪的温床 我们都知道这一点
Slums are breeding grounds for criminals. We all know it.
那不是秘密 来自贫民窟的孩子
It's no secret that children from slums
出了社会很可能会变成恶棍
are potential menaces to society.
-现在我 -你可以再说一次
- I think... - You can say that again.
来自那种地方的孩子都是垃圾
The kids who crawl out of these places are real trash.
我不想跟他们被归为同类
I don't want any part of them.
听我说 我一直都住在贫民窟里
Listen, I...I've lived in a slum all my life.
-等一下 -拜托
- Wait a minute. - Please. I...
我小时候在塞满垃圾的后院里玩耍
I've played in back yards that were filled with garbage.
-你还可以在我身上闻到臭味 -听我说
- Maybe you can still smell it on me. - Listen, sonny...
-这件事无关私人恩怨 -我觉得有关
- Come on, now. There's nothing personal. - But I do.
他说的人不是你 别那么敏感
Come on, fella. He didn't mean you. Let's not be so sensitive.
我能了解那样的感觉
This sensitivity I can understand.
好了 大家别吵了
OK, look. Let's stop the arguing.
我们只是在浪费时间
We're only wasting time.
现在轮到你了 说吧
Your turn down there. Let's go.
轮到我了
I didn't expect a turn.
还以为你们想要说服我
I thought you were all gonna to try to convince me.
那不是你们的原意吗?
Wasn't that the idea?
-一点都没错 -我忘了 他是对的
- That was the idea. - I forgot. He's right.
是他害得我们被困在这里
He's the one keeping us in here.
我们听听他的说法吧
Let's hear what he's got to say.
既然我们已经决定好要这么做
Wait. We decided to do this a certain way.
我们应该要坚持下去
I think we ought to stick to it.
别孩子气了
Oh, stop being a kid, will ya?
你是什么意思? 孩子气
What do you mean, a kid?
你听不懂我的意思吗? 孩-子-气
What do you think I mean? K-I-D: Kid.
我只是想有条不紊地把事情办完
Just because I'm trying to keep this organised
只要你愿意接下这份工作
Here, you take on the responsibility.
我可以把嘴巴闭上
I'll just keep my mouth shut.
你为什么要那么生气? 冷静点
Why are you gettin' so hot? Calm down.
别叫我冷静
Don't tell me to calm down.
快来主持会议
You want to take the chair? Take the chair.
你们看过这种事吗?
Did you ever see such a thing?
你觉得很有趣吗?
You think it's funny?
算了吧 那一点都不重要
Forget it, fella. It's unimportant.
不重要? 你来试试看
Unimportant? Here, you try it.
大家都不想改变现状
Nobody wants to change.
你做的非常好 请坐
You're doing a beautiful job. Sit down.
对 你表现的很好
Yeah, you're doin' great. Just great, fella.
你仍然是会议的主持人
You stay in there and pitch.
好吧 我们来听听别人的说法
All right, let's hear from somebody.
如果你们要我说出我的感觉
Well, if you want me to tell you how I feel about it,
我一点都不在意
it's all right with me.
天啊 我不在乎你做了什么
Boy, I don't care what you do.
好吧 我没有任何的至理名言
All right. I don't have anything brilliant.
我知道的事跟你们一样多
I only know as much as you do.
根据证词 那孩子是有罪的
According to the testimony, the boy looks guilty.
或许人真的是他杀的
Maybe he is.
六天来我坐在法庭上
I sat there in court for six days
听到目击者接连不断提出证词
listening while the evidence built up.
大家的语气都十分肯定
Everybody sounded so positive.
对于这次审判我有很特别的感觉
I began to get a peculiar feeling about this trial.
话不要说的太硬了
I mean, nothing is that positive.
我想要提出一些问题
There are questions I'd have liked to ask.
或许它们毫无意义
Maybe they wouldn't mean anything but...
但我觉得被告并没有
I felt that the defence wasn't conducting
做过完整的交叉讯问
a thorough enough cross-examination.
他遗漏了一些小细节
He let too many things go by-little things.
什么小细节?
What little things?
律师不提出问题
When they don't ask questions,
是因为他们已经知道了答案
it's because they know the answers already.
也很可能是因为那个律师
It's also possible for a lawyer
是大笨蛋 对吧?
to be just plain stupid, isn't it?
那是有可能的
I mean, it's possible.
听起来你已经见过我大舅子了
You sound like you met my brother-in-law once.
我一直让自己站在那孩子的角度来想
I kept putting myself in the kid's place.
我会去请另一个律师来帮我辩护
I'd have asked for another lawyer, I think.
这场审判攸关我的生死
I mean, if I was on trial for my life
我会希望我的律师反驳目击者的证词
I'd want my lawyer to tear the prosecution witnesses to shreds,
至少他该试试看
or at least try to.
听着 这件凶案有一个目击证人
Look, there was one alleged eyewitness to this killing.
还有一个人听到凶案发生过程
Someone else claims he heard the killing,
事后还看到那孩子冲出屋外
saw the boy run out after...
同时还出现了间接证据
and there was circumstantial evidence.
这个案子有两个证人
But those two witnesses were the entire case for the prosecution.
如果他们都错了呢?
Supposing they're wrong?
你是什么意思? 那不是证人的责任吗?
What do you mean? What's the point of having witnesses at all?
如果他们错了呢?
Could they be wrong?
他们在坐上证人席前 都发过了誓
Those people were under oath.
他们只是人 人难免会犯错
They're only people. People make mistakes.
如果他们都错了呢?
Could they be wrong?
-不 我不那么认为 -你真的那么想吗?
- Well, no. I don't think so. - Do you know so?
没有人可以确定那一点
Nobody can know a thing like that.
我们又不是在做科学论证
This isn't an exact science.
没错 你说的对
That's right, it isn't.
现在来谈正事
OK, let's get to the point.
插在死者胸口的折叠刀又是怎么一回事?
What about the switch knife they found in the old man's chest?
等一下 有人还没有发言
Some people haven't talked yet.
我们不该照顺序来吗?
Shouldn't we go in order?
大家都会有机会说话 安静
They'll get a chance to talk. Be quiet a second, will ya?
那孩子承认
What about the knife this fine, upright boy
当晚他买了这把刀 又是怎么一回事?
admitted buying the night of the killing?
我们来谈谈吧
Let's talk about it.
好吧 我们来谈一谈 现在来看看那把凶刀
All right. Let's get it in here and look at it.
我想再看凶刀 团长先生
I'd like to see it again. Mr.Foreman?
为什么还要再看一次呢?
Why do we have to see it again?
他有权利要求审视证物
The gentleman has a right to see exhibits in evidence.
-麻烦你把凶刀拿过来 -没问题
- Say, could you bring us the knife? - The knife? Sure.
凶刀是一项强而有力的证据
The knife and the way it was bought is strong evidence,
你不那么认为吗?
don't you think?
-你说的一点都没错 -很好
- I do. - Good.
我们得一样样地来检视所有的事实
Let's take the facts one at a time.
一 那孩子在八点钟离开家里
One: The boy admitted leaving the house at eight o'clock at night
因为他父亲打了他两巴掌
after being slapped by his father.
不 他没说他"被打巴掌"
No, he didn't say "slapped".
他说他"被揍" 那是不一样的
He said "punched". There's a difference.
他长期受到父亲的殴打
After being hit several times by his father.
二 他跑到附近的二手货店
Two: He went directly to a local junk shop
买了一把
where he bought one of those...
-折叠刀 -折叠刀
- Switch knives. - Switchblade knives.
这不是一把普通的刀子
This wasn't an ordinary knife.
刀柄上刻了漂亮的图案 刀锋与众不同
It had a very unusual carved handle and blade.
店主说他的店里
The storekeeper said it was the only one
只有一把这样的刀子
of its kind he had ever had in stock.
三 八点四十五分左右他在酒吧前遇到一些朋友
Three: He met some friends of his in front of a tavern about 8.45.
对吧?
Am I right so far?
-你说的对 -一点都没错
- Yes, you are. - You bet he is.
他跟朋友一起聊天
He talked with his friends for an hour,
在九点四十五分时离开
leaving them at 9.45.
在这段时间里 他的朋友看到了折叠刀
During this time, they saw the switch knife.
四 他们在法庭指认那把刀子
Four: They identified the death weapon in court
就是凶手使用的凶刀
as that very same knife.
五 大约十点时他回到家里
Five: He arrived home at about ten o'clock.
从此原告律师跟被告的说词
This is where the stories offered by the State
开始出现分歧
and the boy diverge slightly.
被告说他在十一点三十分时出门去看电影
He claims that he went to a movie at about 11.30
凌晨三点十分回到家发现父亲已经死了
returning home at 3.10 to find his father dead
他遭到逮捕
and himself arrested.
他还说逮捕他的两名警官
He also claims that the two detectives
将他丢下楼梯
threw him down a half a flight of stairs.
那把刀子又是怎么一回事?
What happened to the knife?
他说刀子在去看电影的路上
He claims it fell through a hole in his pocket
从口袋的破洞掉了出去
on the way to the movies
约在十一点半到三点十分之间
sometime between 11.30 and 3.10,
之后他再也没有看到那把刀子
and that he never saw it again.
他根本在说谎
Now, there is a tale, gentlemen.
事实非常明显那孩子没有去看电影
I think it's clear the boy never went to the movies that night.
没有人看到他十一点半时离家
No one in the house saw him go out at 11:30.
电影院里也没有人见过他
No one at the theatre identified him.
他完全不记得那部电影的名字
He couldn't even remember the names of the pictures he saw.
真正的事实是 那孩子一直待在家里
What actually happened is this. The boy stayed home
他跟父亲发生争执
had another fight with his father,
他杀了父亲 在十二点十分离家
stabbed him to death and left the house at 10 minutes after 12.
他甚至还把刀子的指纹擦的一干二净
He even wiped the knife clean of fingerprints.
你说这把刀子
Are you trying to tell me that this knife
从那孩子口袋的破洞掉出来
fell through a hole in the boy's pocket
有人捡起它 跑到他家
someone picked it up, went to the boy's house
用它杀死他父亲
and stabbed his father
只为了测试刀子锐不锐利?
with it just to test its sharpness?
很可能是他的刀子不见了
No, but it's possible the boy lost his knife
有人用类似的刀子杀了他父亲
and somebody else stabbed his father with a similar knife.
请看看这把刀子
Take a look at this knife.
它是一把与众不同的刀子
It's a very unusual knife.
我从来没有看过这样的刀子
I've never seen one like it.
卖出它的店主也那么说
Neither had the storekeeper who sold it to the boy.
这未免太巧了吧?
Aren't you asking us to accept an incredible coincidence?
我的意思是或许就是这么巧
I'm just saying a coincidence is possible.
我可不那么认为
And I say it's not possible.
你从哪里弄来那个玩意?
Where did that come from?
这把刀子跟凶刀完全一样!
It's the same knife!
你到底在做什么?
What do you think you're doin'?
你去哪里拿到那把刀子?
Where did you get it?
我昨天晚上出去散步
I went out walking last night.
刚好经过那孩子住的社区
Through the boy's neighbourhood.
我在离那孩子家两条街远的当铺买下它
I bought that at a pawn shop two blocks from the boy's house.
只花了我六块钱
It cost six dollars.
买卖折叠刀是违法的
It's against the law to buy or sell switchblade knives.
我犯了法
That's right. I broke the law.
你这招真的是太妙了
You pulled a real bright trick.
那能证明什么
Now supposing you tell me what it proves.
或许还有十把类似凶刀的刀子
Maybe there are ten knives like that.
-或许是有! -那是什么意思?
- Maybe there are! - What does it mean?
你找到一把类似的刀子
You found a knife like it.
那是了不起的大发现吗?
What's that? The discovery of the age?
我们得相信有人
You think somebody else did the stabbing
拿类似的刀子杀了他父亲?
with exactly the same kind of knife?
-机率只有百万分之一 -那是有可能的!
- The odds are a million to one. - It's possible!
但可能性不是很大
But not very probable.
好吧 大家请坐下
OK, fellas. Let's take our seats.
我们不必站着说话
There's no point standing around all over the place.
他能找到类似凶刀的刀子真的是太有趣了
It's interesting that he'd find a knife exactly like the boy's.
哪里很有趣了?
What's interesting about it? Interesting!
我就是觉得有趣
I just thought it was interesting.
我们十一个人都认为他有罪
Eleven of us still think he's guilty.
你到底想做什么?
Right. What will you accomplish?
你无法改变我们的想法
You're not gonna change anybody's mind.
就算你坚持到底
If you wanna hang this jury, go ahead.
他还是会被判有罪
The kid'll be tried again and found guilty, as sure as he's born.
或许你说的对
You're probably right.
你打算要怎么做呢?
So, what are you gonna do?
我们可能一整晚都会耗在这里
We can be here all night.
只是一夜 可是那孩子会没命的
It's only one night. A boy may die.
我们为什么不干脆在这里扎营?
Well, why don't we just set up house here?
去跟那个警察说他可以休息了
Someone send for a pinochle deck
我们会在这里耗上一阵子
and we'll just sweat the whole thing out right here.
他不该拿这件事开玩笑
I don't think he oughta joke about it.
你要我怎么做?
What do you want me to do about it?
这跟那把刀子有什么关系?
I don't see what the knife has got to do with anything.
有人目睹那孩子杀了自己的父亲
Somebody saw the kid stab his father.
你还需要什么证据?
What more do we need?
我真的不想再听你们废话了
You guys can talk the ears right off my head.
我还要跑三家修车厂
I got three garages going to pot.
赶快把事情办好离开这里吧
So let's get done and get outta here.
对检察官来说那把刀子很重要 他花了
The knife was important to the district attorney. He spent a day...
他只是个小角色 他懂什么?
He's a 15th assistant or something. What does he know?
我们把时间浪费在争吵上
Let's hold it down. These side arguments are only slowin' us up.
怎么样呢? 只有你认为他无罪
Well, what about it? You're the only one.
我要提出一项建议
I have a proposition to make to all of you.
我们何不再投一次票
I'm going to call for another vote.
我要你们十一个人
I want you eleven men to
以书面的方式来做秘密投票
vote by secret written ballot.
我弃权
I'll abstain.
如果你们全都 认为他"有罪"
If there are eleven votes for guilty,
我会赞同你们
I won't stand alone.
我们可以立刻向法官提出有罪的判决
We'll take in a guilty verdict to the judge right now.
但只要有人做出"无罪"的判决
But if anyone votes not guilty,
我们就得待在这里把事情弄清楚
we'll stay here and talk it out.
如果你们愿意 我准备好了
That's it. If you want to try it, I'm ready.
让我们再度受苦吧
All right. Let's do it the hard way.
听起来很公平 大家都同意吗?
That sounds fair. Everyone agreed?
有人反对吗?
Anyone doesn't agree?
好了 请帮忙传下去
OK, pass these along.
有罪
Guilty.
无罪
Not guilty.
有罪
Guilty.
天啊 怎么会这样?
Boy, how do you like that?
又有一个混蛋在搞破坏!
And another chap flips his wings!
好了 是谁干的? 我想要知道
All right. Who was it? Come on, I wanna know.
对不起 这是秘密投票
Excuse me. This was a secret ballot.
大家都说好了
We all agreed on that, no?
如果他不想被公开
If the gentleman wants it to remain secret...
你是什么意思? 秘密?
Secret? What do you mean?
陪审团室里没有任何秘密
There are no secrets in a jury room.
我知道是谁干的
I know who it was.
你真的是很厉害
Brother, you really are somethin'.
你坐在这里投票认为他有罪
You vote guilty like the rest of us,
那家伙的胡言乱语说动了你
then some golden-voiced preacher tears your heart out
他认为那孩子不可能杀人
some underprivileged kid couldn't help becoming a murderer
于是你改变了心意
and you change your vote.
那真的太
If that isn't the most sickening...
你为什么不丢些铜板到他的破碗去呢?
Why don't you drop a quarter in his collection box?
等一下
Oh, now just wait a...
你不能那样子跟我说话
Listen, you can't talk to me like that.
你以为你是什么东西?
Who do you think you are?
冷静点
Calm down, calm down. It doesn't matter.
他太激动了 快坐下
He's very excitable. Sit down.
激动? 我当然很激动!
Excitable? You bet I'm excitable!
我们要把一个罪有应得的家伙送上电椅
We're tryin' to put a guilty man in the chair, where he belongs.
他满口胡言乱语我们相信了!
Someone starts tellin' us fairy tales and we're listenin'!
少来了
Come on
你为什么要改变心意?
What made you change your vote?
改变心意的人不是他 是我
He didn't change his vote. I did.
-太棒了 -我就知道
- Oh, fine. - I knew it.
你要我告诉你为什么吗?
Would you like me to tell you why?
我不想听
No, I wouldn't like you to tell me why.
我想把话说清楚
I'd like to anyway, if you don't mind.
我们非得听这些废话不可吗?
Do we have to listen to this?
-他有话想说 -谢谢你
- The man wants to talk. - Thank you.
这位先生一直孤军奋战地跟我们对抗
This gentleman has been standing alone against us.
他并没有说那孩子无罪
He doesn't say the boy is not guilty.
他只是说他无法确定他有罪
He just isn't sure.
要孤军奋战对抗荒谬的言论并不容易
It's not easy to stand alone against the ridicule of others.
所以他孤注一掷争取支持
So he gambled for support
我支持他因为我赞同他的动机
and I gave it to him. I respect his motives.
那个孩子或许真的杀了人
The boy on trial is probably guilty
但我想听到更多的证词
but I want to hear more.
现在的票数是十比二
The vote is ten to two.
我在讲话! 你没有权利离开!
I'm talking! You have no right to leave this room!
他不会听你说话
He can't hear you.
他死都不会听的 我们坐下吧
He never will. Let's sit down.
可以继续了吗?
Shall we continue?
我觉得我们应该休息一下
Well, I think we ought to take a break.
有人进了洗手间
You know, one man's inside
我觉得我们应该等他
and I think we ought to wait for him.
看来我们真的被困在这里了
Looks like we're really hung up here, huh?
那老头会做出那种事
I mean, that thing with the old man,
真是令人意想不到
that was pretty unexpected.
真希望我能想出办法突破这个困局
Wish I could figure out some way we could break it up.
你知道吗? 在广告界
You know, in advertising...
我提过我在广告公司工作吗?
I told you I worked in an agency?
有一些怪人在那里工作
Some pretty strange people work there.
我觉得他们一点都不奇怪
Well, not strange, really.
只是他们表达自己的方式很特别
I guess it's just they have peculiar ways of expressing themselves.
我猜在你那一行也是一样的吧?
I suppose it's the same in your business too, huh?
-你是做哪一行的? -我是个钟表匠
- What do you do? - I'm a watchmaker.
真的吗?
Really?
我以为最棒的钟表匠都在欧洲
I imagine the finest watchmakers in the world come from Europe.
在公司里要是遇到这种情形
Anyway, in an agency, when we reach a point like this...
在广告公司里
I'm telling him, in an ad agency
要是遇到这种情形
when a point like this is reached in a meeting
总会有人想出妙点子来
there's always some character ready with an idea, see.
我真的都快笑死了
It kills me.
那真的很奇怪
It's the weirdest thing,
他们总是用一句话来说出自己的心声
the way they sometimes precede their idea with a phrase.
总会有个广告业务人员站起来说
Like, some account exec will get up and he'll say:
"好了 我想到一个点子
"OK, here's an idea.
我们把它升上旗杆
Let's...run it up the flagpole
看看会不会有人向它敬礼"
and see if anyone salutes it."
虽然挺蠢的 但很好笑
I mean, it's idiotic, but it's funny.
我刚刚太激动了一点
I...got a little excited back there.
我无意要为难大家
I...didn't mean to get nasty.
还好你不是那一种
Glad you're not one of those
会被情绪影响的人
who lets these emotional appeals influence him.
我不知道那个电扇到底是哪里有问题
I don't know what's the matter with that fan.
-你是业务员吗? -我是建筑师
- Are you a salesman? - I'm an architect.
你知道什么叫做软性推销?
You know what the soft sell is?
你有这个技能 相信我
Well, you've got it, believe me.
我用的技巧跟别人不一样
I've got a different technique.
说说笑话 陪客人喝几杯
Laughs, drinks, jokes,
耍耍小手段 你懂吧?
tricks. You know?
我懂
Yeah.
抓住他们生活的脉动 那就是我的名言
Hit 'em where they live , that's my motto.
去年我靠卖橘皮果酱赚了两万七
I made 27 grand last year sellin' marmalade.
成绩还不错
That's not bad.
毕竟我卖的可是橘皮果酱
I mean, you know, considerin' marmalade.
待在这里能得到什么好处? 刺激吗?
What are you gettin' out of this? Kicks?
难不成有人撞到你的头
Or did somebody bump you on the head once
你到现在还耿耿于怀吗?
and you haven't gotten over it?
或许是吧
Maybe.
你们全都是不切实际的家伙
You know, you do- gooders are all alike.
老是把自己的快乐
You're always blowin' your stacks
建立在别人的痛苦上
over some guy that fanned.
你为什么要浪费我们的时间?
But what are you wastin' our time for?
捐点钱做好事
Why don't you donate five dollars to the cause?
或许能让你觉得舒服点
Maybe it'll make you feel better.
这个孩子有罪
This kid is guilty, pal.
那简直是再明显不过了
It's as plain as the nose on your face.
我们为什么还要继续浪费时间?
So why don't we stop wastin' our time here?
吵到最后大家的喉咙都痛了
We're gonna all get sore throats if we keep it up.
你被困在这里
What difference does it make
或是去看球赛那又有什么差别呢?
if you get it here or at the ball game?
没有差别 兄弟
No difference, pal.
完全没有差别
No difference at all.
他们还挺不错的 对吧?
Nice bunch of guys, huh?
他们跟其他人都一样
They're about the same as anyone else.
天啊 今天真的是够惨的了
Boy, what a murderous day.
你觉得这样还会继续很久吗?
Do you think we'll be much longer?
我不知道
I don't know.
他绝对有罪 全世界没有一个人会怀疑
He's guilty for sure. Not a doubt in the whole world.
我们早该做出裁决
We should've... We should've been done already.
我并不介意 这比上班好玩多了
Oh, I don't mind, you know. Beats workin'.
你认为他无罪 对吧?
You think he's not guilty, huh?
我不知道 或许是吧
I don't know. It's possible.
我不认识你
Well, I don't know you,
但我很肯定你从未犯过错
but I'm bettin' you've never been wronger in your life.
你是在浪费你的时间
You're wastin' your time. You ought to wrap it up.
如果接受审判的人是你自己呢?
Supposing you were the one who was on trial?
我不想回答假设性的问题
Well, I'm not used to supposin'.
我只是一个上班族 要动脑筋的人是我老板
I'm just a workin' man. My boss does the supposin'.
但我会试试看的
But I'll try one.
假设你真的可以说服我们每一个人
Supposin' you talk us all out of this and...
但那孩子真的拿刀子杀了他父亲呢?
the kid really did knife his father, huh?
准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
对不起 大帅哥
Sorry, blue eyes.
-随便挑一个 -好了 大家坐下吧
- Well, where else? - OK, fellas. Let's take our seats.
看来我们得留在这里吃晚餐
Looks like we'll be here for dinner.
好了 快点来谈正式 谁想第一个发言?
OK, now let's get down to business. Who wants to start?
-我有话要说 -请说
- I will. - OK, go. You, down there.
住在凶案现场楼下的老头
The old man who lived downstairs
说他听到那孩子大叫着
says he heard the kid yell
"我要杀了你"
"I'm gonna kill ya."
一秒后他听到有人摔倒的声音
A second later, he heard the body hit the floor.
他跑到门口看到那孩子夺门而出
He ran to the door and saw the kid run out of the house.
你们想到了什么呢?
What's that mean to you?
隔了一层天花板他能听得多清楚呢?
I wonder how clearly he heard the boy's voice through the ceiling.
他并非透过天花板 那时窗户是打开的
He didn't. The window was open.
那是一个炎热的夜晚
So was the one upstairs. It was a hot night.
那是另一回事 要听清楚对方的声音并不容易
It was another apartment. It's not easy to identify a shouting voice.
他在庭上指认出那孩子的声音
He identified it in court.
别忘了住在对街的女士
The lady across the street
她看到那孩子拿刀刺死他父亲
looked right in the open window and saw the stabbing.
难道对你来说这还不够吗?
Isn't that enough for you?
的确是不够
No, it isn't.
这简直就是在对牛弹琴
Boy, how do you like this guy? It's like talkin' into a dead phone.
她是透过电车的车窗看到凶案发生的经过
She said she saw it through the windows of a moving el train.
电车一共有六节车厢
There were six cars on the train.
她透过最后两节车厢目睹凶案经过
She saw it through the last two.
她记得所有的细节
She remembered insignificant details.
那是无庸置疑的证据
How can you argue with that?
你们曾经想过
Has anybody here any idea
电车要花多少时间
how long it would take an el...
这不是在玩游戏
This isn't a game.
你看到了吗? 他胆子真大!
Did you see him? The nerve!
他简直是胆大包天
The absolute nerve!
好了 别这样
Forget it. It's not important.
这不是在玩游戏吗?
This isn't a game?
-冷静点 -他以为他是什么东西?
- Calm down. - Who does he think he is?
别闹了
Forget it now.
你们曾经想过电车
Has anybody any idea how long it takes an el train
要花多少时间才能完全通过某一点吗?
at medium speed to pass a given point?
-我不知道 -你觉得呢?
- I wouldn't have any idea. - What do you think?
我不知道 或许十到十二秒吧
I don't know. Ten, twelve seconds?
很不错 其他人呢?
A pretty good guess. Anyone else?
他说的有道理
Sounds right to me.
我们为什么要玩猜谜游戏?
What's the guessing game for?
-你觉得呢? -十秒钟吧
- What do you say? - Ten seconds.
好吧 假设真的是十秒钟 你想表达什么呢?
All right. Say 10 seconds. What are you getting at?
有六节车厢的电车要花十秒钟才能通过某一个点
It takes a six-car el train ten seconds to pass a given point.
假设那一点
Say the given point is the open window of the room
就是发生凶案的房间窗口
where the killing took place.
在那里一伸手几乎就可以摸到铁轨
You can reach out and almost touch the el tracks, right?
我要问你们一个问题
Now let me ask you this.
你们之中有人曾住在铁轨旁边吗?
Has anyone here ever lived near the el tracks?
我刚油漆完一间可以俯视电车线的公寓
I just finished painting an apartment that overlooked an el line.
花了三天的时间
It took three days.
-那是什么样的感觉呢? -你是什么意思?
- What was it like? - What you means?
-很吵吗? -天啊!
- Noisy? - Oh, brother!
那不重要 因为大家都昏沉沉的
No matter. We were punchy.
我曾经住在电车线附近
I lived in an apartment near the el line once.
只要有电车通过
When the window's open,
噪音大到令人难以忍受
the train noise is almost unbearable.
甚至吵得你无法思考
You can hardly hear yourself think.
你就不能直接讲重点吗?
Will you get to the point?
我会的 稍安勿躁
I will. Just a minute.
请回想一下两个证人的证词
Now, let's take two pieces of testimony
把它们拼凑在一起
and try to put them together.
首先 住在楼下公寓的老人
First: The old man in the apartment downstairs.
他听到那孩子说 "我要杀了你"
He says he heard the boy say "I'm gonna kill you"
一秒后他听到有人摔倒在地的声音
and a split second later heard a body hit the floor.
-没错 -第二点
- Right. - Second...
那女人发誓说
The woman across the street swore positively
当她从窗户往外看时
she looked out of the window
她透过电车最后两节车厢
and saw the killing through the last two cars
看到凶案发生的经过
of a passing el train-the last two cars.
-你到底想说什么? -等一下
- What are you givin' us here? - Now, just a minute.
我们都同意电车得花十秒钟
We've agreed that it takes ten seconds
才能完全通过某一点
for a train to pass a given point.
因为她是透过最后两节车厢看到凶案发生的经过
Since the woman saw the killing through the last two cars
我们可以推测出死者
we can assume that the body hit the floor
是在电车经过时倒在地上
just as the train went by.
因此电车经过老人家窗口时发出轰隆隆的噪音
Therefore, the train had been roaring by the old man's window
过了十秒后死者倒在地上
a full ten seconds before the body hit the floor.
他说他听到被告说"我要杀了你"
The old man hearing the boy said"I'm gonna kill you"
一秒后听到有人跌在地上
body hitting the floor a second later
所以他听到那孩子说话的同时
would have had to hear the boy's words
电车刚好经过他家窗口!
with the el roaring past his nose!
-他不可能听得到 -他真的听到了
- It's not possible he heard it. - Of course he heard it.
你相信他的说法?
Do you think so?
那孩子是扯着喉咙大叫
He said he yelled at the top of his voice.
当时刚好有电车通过
He couldn't have identified the voice
他不可能认得出那孩子的声音
with the el roaring by.
这是在几秒内发生的事
It was a matter of seconds!
没有人可以测量的那么准确
Nobody can be that accurate.
我认为能送那孩子上电椅的证词
Testimony that could put a boy into the electric chair
必须非常准确才行
should be that accurate.
我认为他根本就听不出来
I don't think he could have heard it.
或许那么吵他真的听不出来
Maybe he didn't, with all that el noise.
你在胡说什么?
What are you people talkin' about?
他的确可能会听不清楚
It stands to reason he couldn't have.
他为什么要说谎? 那对他有什么好处?
Why lie? What's he got to gain?
或许他想引起别人的注意
Attention, maybe.
你既然想出这么多理论 把它们卖给报社吧
You keep comin' in with bright sayings. Send 'em to a paper!
一份稿费是三块钱!
They pay $3 apiece!
你为什么要那样子对他说话?
What are you talkin' to him like that for?
会那样子跟老人说话的人
A guy who talks like that to an old man
应该要受到谴责
really oughta get stepped on.
你得学着去尊敬别人 先生
You oughta have more respect, mister.
你敢再那样子跟他说话
You say stuff like that to him again...
我一定会给你好看
I'm gonna lay you out.
好了 你想说什么就说吧
You go ahead. You say anything you like.
你觉得那个老人为什么要说谎呢?
Why do you think the old man might lie?
我在法庭上一直盯着他看
It was just that I looked at him for a very long time.
他穿的外套在肩膀的部份裂开了
The seam of his jacket was split, under the shoulder.
你们注意到了吗?
Did you notice that?
我是说他上法庭却穿成那个样子
I mean, to come into court like that.
他是个穿着破外套的老头子
He was a very old man in a torn jacket.
而且他走上证人席的步伐缓慢
And he walked very slowly to the stand.
他的左脚一跛一跛的
He was dragging his left leg
却努力地想要掩饰它
and trying to hide it
因为他觉得自己很丢脸
because he was ashamed.
我认为我比你们任何一个人都了解那个老头子
I think I know this man better than anyone here.
他是个安静 怯懦 不起眼的老头子
This is a quiet, frightened, insignificant old man who...
一辈子无所成
who has been nothing all his life.
没有人认得他
Who has never had recognition
他的名字也没有上过报
or his name in the newspapers.
没有人认得他 也不会听他说话
Nobody knows him. Nobody quotes him.
七十五年来没有人征询过他的意见
Nobody seeks his advice after 75 years.
各位 默默无闻是一件令人伤感的事
Gentlemen, that's a very sad thing-to mean nothing.
像他那样的人会希望别人去询问他的意见
A man like this needs to be quoted,
有人会听他说话
to be listened to.
即使只有一次询问他 对他来说都很重要
To be quoted just once-very important to him.
要他放弃这个机会真的很难
It would be so hard for him to recede into the background.
等等
Wait a minute.
他说谎只为了体会当大人物的滋味?
Are you tellin' us he'd lie just so he could be important once?
不 事实上他不算是说谎
No. He wouldn't really lie.
或许他幻想他真的听到那些话
But perhaps he made himself believe he heard those words
认为凶手就是那个男孩
and recognised the boy's face.
这个说法太妙了
That's the most fantastic story ever.
你怎么编得出这样的故事
How can you make up a thing like that?
你又知道多少呢?
What do you know about it?
谁想吃喉糖?
Does anybody want a cough drop?
给我一颗吧
I'll take one.
我还是不明白你们为什么会认为他无罪
I still don't see how anybody can think he's not guilty.
还有一件事我想跟你们讨论一下
There's something else I'd like to talk about for a minute.
我们证明了那老头
We've proved the old man
听不到那孩子说"我要杀了你"
couldn't have heard the boy say "I'm gonna kill you."
你根本没有证明任何事
You didn't prove it at all!
假设他真的听到了
Wait. Supposing he really did hear it?
你们有多常说这句话呢?
This phrase, how many times have all of us used it?
应该超过好几千次吧
Probably thousands.
"我非杀了你不可"
"I could kill you for that."
"你再这样 我就杀了你"
"Junior, do that again and I'll kill you."
"洛基 快进来杀了他"
"Rocky, kill him."
那不代表我们真的要
It doesn't mean we'd really kill anybody.
你到底想做什么?
What you wanna to give us here?
他说"我要杀了你"
The kid yelled it at the top of his lungs.
别告诉我他不是这个意思
Don't tell me he didn't mean it.
任何人像他那样说话 都是认真的
Anybody says it like that, they mean it!
天啊 现在我真的不知道了
Gee, I don't know.
几个星期前
I was arguing with the guy
我跟一位工作伙伴发生争执
I work next to at the bank a few weeks ago.
他骂我是白痴 于是我对他破口大骂
He called me an idiot, so I yelled at him.
他要你们去相信他编的故事!
This guy is trying to make you believe what isn't so!
被告放话要杀人他真的动手了!
The kid said he'd kill him and he did!
那孩子如果真的想杀人
Do you really think the boy'd shout it out
他会到处嚷嚷让邻居知道吗?
so the whole neighbourhood could hear?
他太聪明了
He's much too bright for that.
聪明? 他只是个不学无术的混混一般的
Bright? He's a common, ignorant slob.
他连英语都说不好
He don't even speak good English.
甚至连正确的语法都不会
He doesn't even speak good English.
团长先生
Mr.Foreman,
我改变了心意 那个孩子应该是无罪
I'd like to change my vote to not guilty.
-你说什么? -你都听到了
- You what? - You heard me.
-你确定? -我非常确定
- Are you sure? - Yeah, I'm sure.
九比三有罪那一方占优势
The vote is nine to three in favour of guilty.
但这还不是最后的结论 对吧
Well, if this isn't the livin' end! huh?
你为什么会相信
What are you basin' it on?
这个家伙编出来的故事?
Stories this guy made up?
你应该去写侦探小说
You oughta write for one of those kooky detective magazines,
你一定可以大赚一票的
make a fortune.
连那孩子的律师都知道
For cryin' out loud, the kid's own lawyer knew
他根本没有胜诉的机会
he didn't stand a chance.
从一开始
Right from the beginning,
他的律师就知道了
his own lawyer knew, and you could see it.
天啊 听我说
Boy, oh boy, I'm telling ya.
这个家伙真的很厉害
This guy here is really somethin'.
那孩子请了律师
The kid had a lawyer, didn't he?
应该由他来帮他打官司
He presented his case, not you.
为什么你有那么多的话可说?
How come you say so much?
律师的话并不完全是正确的
Lawyers aren't infallible.
他是法庭指派的律师
He was court-appointed.
那是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
他很可能并不想出庭打这场官司
He didn't want the case
虽然他真的出庭了
or he resented being appointed.
从这个案子他捞不到任何好处
It's the kind of case
赚不到钱 得不到名声
that brings no money, no glory,
连胜诉的机会都是微乎其微
not much chance of winning.
对一位年轻律师来说
That's not a very promising situation
这不是一个好案子
for a young lawyer.
他得去相信他的客户是无罪的
He'd really have to believe in his client to put up a good case.
但他并没有那么做
Obviously he didn't.
他当然不会那么做
Of course he didn't.
谁会那么做呢?
Who the heck could?
或许某人的妈妈或是某个人
Except maybe some guy's mother or somebody.
听我说 现在已经很晚了 别再耗下去了
Oh, look. Will you look at the time? Come on.
对不起 我做了一些笔记
Pardon me. I have made some notes here
我有一些话 想要告诉你们
and I would like, please, to say something.
我一直非常仔细地在听证人陈述证词
I have been listening very carefully and...
看起来这位先生说的话非常有道理
it seems to me that this man has some very good points to make.
从法庭上的证词看来
From what was presented at the trial,
这孩子似乎是有罪
the boy looks guilty, on the surface.
-如果我们深入去 -少来了
- But maybe if we go deeper... - Come on, will ya?
我有一个问题
There is a question I would like to ask.
假设那个孩子真的杀了人
Let us assume that the boy really did commit the murder.
案发的时间是十二点十分
Now, this happened at 10 minutes after 12.
他是如何被警方逮捕的呢?
Now, how was he caught by the police?
他是在三点左右 回到家里
He came back home... at three o'clock or so
在家里被两名警官逮捕
and he was captured by two detectives in the hallway of his house.
我的问题是
Now, my question is:
如果他真的杀了他的父亲
If he really had killed his father
为什么他会在三个小时后回到家里?
why would he come back home three hours later?
难道他不怕会被逮到吗?
Wouldn't he be afraid of being caught?
他是回来拿刀子的
He came home for his knife.
他不想让刀子继续插在死者胸口上
It's not nice to leave knives in people's chests.
对 而且死的人是他老爸
Yeah, especially relatives'.
我一点都不觉得好笑
I don't see anything funny about it.
他知道会有人指认出那是他的刀子
The boy knew the knife could be identified.
他得抢在警察前面拿走刀子
He had to get it before the police did.
如果他知道凶刀会被指认出来
If he knew the knife could be identified,
案发时他为什么要把它留在现场?
why did he leave it there in the first place?
我们可以假设那孩子杀了父亲后
I think we can assume the boy ran out in a state of panic,
慌张地逃离现场
having just killed his father.
他冷静下来后
He calmed down
才发现他把刀子留在现场
and realised he'd left his knife there.
这得视你对慌张的定义来做判断
This, then, depends on your definition of panic.
他必须非常地冷静
He would have had to be calm enough
才会想到要把刀子的指纹擦干净
to wipe off any fingerprints left on the knife.
他什么时候感到慌张
Now, where did this panic start
又在什么时候冷静下来的呢?
and where did it end?
你投了有罪一票 你到底站在哪一边?
You voted guilty. What side are you on?
我不必效忠于任何一边
I don't believe I have to be loyal to one side or the other.
我只是提出了我的疑问
I'm simply asking questions.
这真的已经超出了我的理解范围 但是
This is just off the top of my head but...
如果我是他我真的杀了人
If I'd done the stabbing,
我会回案发现场取回刀子
I'd take a chance and go back for the knife.
他认为没有人看到他离开现场
I'll bet he figured nobody'd seen him running out
尸体要到隔天才会被发现
and the body wouldn't be discovered till the next day.
那时是三更半夜的
After all, it was the middle of the night.
他认为没有人会发现尸体
He figured it'd be found the next day.
对不起 那就是我的重点
Pardon. This is my whole point.
那女人在法庭上说
The woman across the street testified that
在凶案发生之后
the moment after she saw the killing that is
在电车经过后不久
a moment after the train went by
她放声大叫 并且打电话报警
she screamed, and then went to telephone the police.
那个孩子一定听到了尖叫声
Now, the boy certainly must have heard the scream.
他一定知道有人看到他杀人
So he knew that somebody saw something.
我想他是打死都不会回家的
I just don't think that he would have gone back.
两个可能
Two things.
或许他太过惊慌没有听到尖叫声
One: He may not have heard the scream.
或许她没有叫得很大声
Perhaps it wasn't very loud.
或许他没有想到
Two: If he did, he may not have connected it
她是看到他杀人才会放声大叫
with his own acts.
在他住的地方听见尖叫声是司空见惯的事
He lived in a neighbourhood where screams were commonplace.
-事情就是那么简单 -或许是吧
- There's your answer. - Maybe.
或是他真的杀了他父亲
Maybe the boy did kill his father.
他没有听到尖叫声
Didn't hear the scream...
他慌张地冲出屋子
did run out in a panic,
事后他冷静下来
calmed down later...
冒着被抓的风险
and came back for the knife,
回家去拿他的刀子
risking being caught by the police.
或许这就是事实 或许根本不是这么一回事
Maybe those things happened, but maybe they didn't.
还有很多疑点能让我们去怀疑
There's enough doubt to wonder
案发时他到底在不在现场
if he was there at all at the time of the killing.
你在胡说什么?
What do you mean?
那个老头子看到他冲出屋外
Didn't the old man see him running out of the house?
他是在扭曲事实
He's twisting the facts.
十二点十分时那个老人
Did or didn't the old man see the kid
到底有没有看到被告?
running out of the house at 12.10?
他到底有没有看到?
Well, did or didn't he?
他说他看到了
He says he did.
他说他看到了? 天啊 你怎么能这样?
Says he did? Boy, how do you like that?
证人也是会犯错的
Witnesses can make mistakes.
没错 那都是你在胡说八道!
Sure, when you want them to!
他根本没有说谎!
Or when he wants them to!
小声一点
Keep the yelling down.
或许我们该大声地说出来
Maybe we need a little yelling.
这些家伙越来越过份了
These guys keep going off every which way.
他到底有没有听到这有什么分别?
Did hear the scream, didn't hear it-what difference does it make?
你们只会去讨论那些微乎其微的小细节
You're talking about little details
却忘了最重要的事
and forgetting the important stuff.
-我提议再投一次票 -我在说话!
- I call for another vote. - I'm talking here!
有人要求再投一次票
Another vote called for.
大家请坐下
Now let's take our seats.
我从来没看过有人把时间浪费在这种小事上
I never saw so much time spent on nothin'.
只要一下子就好了
It only takes a second.
最快的方法是先表决无罪的部份
OK, I guess the fastest way is to find out who's voting not guilty.
要投无罪一票的人请举手
All those voting not guilty, please raise your hands.
还是一样 三票无罪 九票有罪
Still the same. One, two, three not guilty. Nine guilty.
听我说
So now where are we?
再这样耗下去我们得在这里待到下星期二
We can yakety-yak till next Tuesday.
这对我们有什么好处呢?
Where's it getting us?
对不起 我要投无罪一票
Pardon. I vote not guilty.
他在胡说什么?
What are you talkin' about?
大家全都疯了
I mean, we're all goin' crazy in here or somethin'.
那个孩子有罪 你们为什么不愿意相信事实?
The kid is guilty. Why don't you listen to the facts?
这个案子会变成一个大笑话
Tell them, will ya? This is gettin' to be a joke.
票数是八比四 有罪占优势
The vote is eight to four in favour of guilty.
这是怎么一回事?
What is this?
支持弱势团体周到了吗?
Love Your Underprivileged Brother Week?
告诉我你为什么会改变心意
I want you to tell me why you changed your vote.
把理由给我说清楚
Give me reasons.
我不必为我的决定辩护
I don't have to defend my decision to you.
我心里头出现了合理的怀疑
There is a reasonable doubt in my mind.
什么怀疑? 证词非常明确 听我说
Reasonable doubt? Nothing but words. Look at this.
有人看到你认为无罪的那个孩子
The kid you just decided isn't guilty was seen
拿刀杀了他的父亲!
ramming this into his father!
那又是怎么一回事?
What about this, Mr.Reasonable Doubt?
那并不是凶刀 你还记得吗?
That's not the knife, remember?
太棒了!
Oh, brilliant!
我得告诉你们这件事太疯狂了
I'm tellin' you, this is the craziest.
我们到底要相信什么?
I mean, what are we supposed to believe?
你们凭空编出许多故事
You're pullin' stories out of thin air.
这家伙要是看过丹柏西跟佛波的比赛
A guy like this, if he's sittin' ringside at the Dempsey-Firpo fight
或许他会告诉你们
he'd be trying to tell you that...
那个老头又是怎么一回事?
Look. Now what about the old man?
我们要相信他没有跑到门边
Are we supposed to believe
在案发后十五秒他没有看到那孩子冲出屋外?
he didn't see the kid tearin' down the steps 15 seconds after the killing?
他那么说只是想引人注意 对吧?
He's just sayin' so to be important, right?
-你到底想说什么? -等一下
- What's the point of it all? - Hold it.
巴尔的摩队的球迷欢声雷动
The Baltimore rooter is heard from again.
球员击出安打现场纸花四射
And pop-ups are fallin' for base hits.
那个老头说他跑到了门口了吗?
Did the old man say he ran to the door?
他用跑的或用走的又有什么差别?
What's the difference?
总之他是到了门口
He got there, didn't he?
-等一下 -我确定他说他是用跑的
- Hold on a second. - He said he ran. At least I think he did.
我不记得了 他根本就没办法跑步
I don't remember, but I don't see how he could have run.
他说他从房间跑到了门口
He said he wentfrom his bedroom to the front door.
这还不够吗?
Isn't that enough?
-他的房间在哪里? -就在走廊的尽头
- Where was the bedroom? - Down the hall.
你记得所有的细节却不记得那一点?
You remember everything, don't you remember that?
我是不记得了 我想看看那栋公寓的配置图
No. I want to see a diagram of the apartment.
我们为什么不叫他们再开一次庭?
Why don't we have him on trial again?
只有你想看公寓的配置图
You're the only one wants to see exhibits.
-我也想看 -我不想再浪费时间了
- I want to see this one, too. - I'd like to stop wastin' time.
如果我们要把时间浪费在这些胡言乱语上
If we're gonna wade through that nonsense about the body...
这不是在浪费时间 我想要知道
No, but I'd like to know if an old man
一个跛脚的老人
who drags one foot cos he had a stroke
能不能在十五秒内从他的房间跑到门口
can get from his bedroom to his front door in 15 seconds.
-是二十秒才对 -他说十五秒
- He said 20. - He said 15.
他要二十秒 你为什么要扭曲事实?
20. What are you tryin' to distort?
他说十五秒
He said 15.
他怎么会知道十五秒到底是多久?
How does he know how long 15 seconds is? You can't judge that.
他说十五秒 他非常肯定
He said 15. He was positive about it.
他是个老头子!
He was an old man!
他的脑袋有一半的时间不太清楚!
Half the time, he was confused.
他怎么能那么肯定他看到的事都是对的?
How could he be positive about anything?
我不知道你想证明什么
I don't see what you're going to prove.
这老头的确看到那个孩子了
The man said he saw the boy running out.
我们来看看他说的话是不是真的
Let's see if the details bear him out.
当有人倒在地板上之后
As the body hit the floor,
他说他听到楼上传来脚步声
he said he heard footsteps upstairs,
脚步声一路传到了门口
running to the front door.
他听到门打开的声音 还听到有人冲下楼
Heard the upstairs door open, the footsteps start down.
他跑到大门口 非常肯定整个过程只有十五秒
He said he got to his own door in, at most, 15 seconds.
-凶手拔腿就跑 -可能他没有
- If the killer ran immediately... - Maybe he didn't.
那老头真的是那么说的
The old man said he did.
你应该去参加吹毛求疵大会
You oughta be at that hair-splitters' convention.
你为什么还要装出自以为聪明的样子?
Why don't you stop making smart remarks?
朋友
My friend,
当陪审员一天只能赚三块钱
for your three dollars a day you have to listen to everything.
这就是案发现场
Here's the apartment.
老人的家就在楼下隔局完全是一样的
The old man's was directly beneath and exactly the same.
这是车轨 卧室 客厅
Here are the el tracks, the bedroom, living room,
厨房 浴室 这是走廊 楼梯
kitchen, bathroom hall, stairs.
当时老人在他的卧房里
The old man was in this bedroom here.
他打开了房门 一路冲到走廊的另一端
He says he crossed to the door, walked down the hall
他及时打开大门
opened the door,
看到那孩子冲下楼梯 对吧?
just in time to see the boy running down the stairs. Am I right?
他一再陈述着这样的证词
That's the story, for the 19th time.
离他听到有人倒在地上的声音只差了十五秒
15 seconds after the body hit the floor.
-没错 -现在让我们来看看
- Correct. - Now, let's see. It was...
床铺离房门有十二尺 走廊有四十三尺长
It's 12 feet from the bed to the door. The hall is 43 feet.
他得走上十二尺的距离 打开房门
He would have had to walk 12 feet, open the bedroom door
走过四十三尺长的走廊再打开大门
walk 43 feet down and open the front door,
一共只花掉十五秒
all in 15 seconds.
-你觉得他办得到吗? -当然可以
- Could he have done it? - Sure.
他走起路来非常慢
He walks slowly.
还要法警来扶他
He needed help into the witness chair.
你讲得好像这条路很远
You make it sound like a long walk.
对一个中过风的老人来说这段路的确很远
For an old man who had a stroke, it is.
-你在做什么? -我打算亲自实验一下
- What are you doin'? - I'm gonna try it.
什么? 他的律师为什么不那么做?
What do you mean? Why didn't his lawyer bring it up?
-或许他没有想到这一点 -你是什么意思?
- Maybe he just didn't think of it. - What do you mean?
-这太明显了 -你认为他是白痴吗?
- It's obvious. - Do you think he's an idiot?
他没有提出这一点因为这对他很不利
He didn't bring it up because he knew it'd hurt his case.
你觉得呢?
What you think about it?
他没有提出这一点
Or because it would have meant
因为那证明了老人在说谎
bullying and badgering a helpless old man.
陪审团不喜欢这样的事
That doesn't sit well with a jury.
律师会尽量避免发生这种事
Most lawyers avoid it.
他到底是个什么样的人?
What kind of a bum is he?
我一直在问这个问题
That's what I'm asking.
请把那张椅子拿过来给我
Pass me that chair.
我们用这些椅子来代表床
Those two chairs are the old man's bed.
我要量出十二尺的距离
I just paced off 12 feet.
这里就是房门口
This is the bedroom door.
你不能那样子重建现场
That's crazy. You can't re-create a thing like that.
我要走到那道墙边再走回来
I'll pace from that wall and back again.
真疯狂
This is insane.
你为什么要浪费大家的时间 把我们困在这里?
What are you wasting everybody's time for?
根据你的说法这个部份 只花十五秒
According to you, it'll only take 15 seconds.
我们要证明这一点
We can spare that.
喂 别吹了
Come on. Knock it off.
好吧 大天才
OK. OK, OK, killer.
你站在那里当大门
Will you stand there and mark the front door?
还记得吗? 当时大门上了门链
It was chain-locked, remember.
-谁的手表有秒针? -我的手表有
- Who's got a watch with a second hand? - I have.
你准备好后就跺脚暗示我
Stamp your foot. That'll be the body falling.
然后开始帮我计时
You can time me from there.
我们要来玩比手划脚的游戏吗?
What are we gonna do, play charades?
我们还在等什么?
What are we waiting for?
我得等到秒针归零才能开始计时
I wanna wait till the second hand reaches 60.
少来了!
Aw, come on!
快一点 他走起路来的速度比你快两倍
Come on, speed it up. He can walk twice as fast as that.
你要我走快一点吗 没问题
If you want me to walk faster than that, I will.
-开锁 打开门 停 -好
- Lock. Door. Stop. - Right.
-时间是多少? -四十一秒整
- What's the time? - Exactly...41 seconds.
我想这才是真正的事实
This is what I think happened.
案发数小时前 老人听到了争吵声
The old man heard the fight a few hours earlier.
后来他躺在床上 听到有人倒在地上的声音
When he's in bed, he heard the body hit the floor
他听到了尖叫声
heard the woman scream,
拼了老命地跑到大门口
got to his front door as fast as he could
他听到了脚步声以为是那个孩子
heard somebody running and assumed it was the boy.
-我想那是有可能的 -那都是他的推测
- I think that's possible. - Assumed?
我看过各式各样的骗局
Brother, I've seen all kinds of dishonesty in my day,
但你的示范真的是太惊人了
but this little display takes the cake.
你们带着一份热忱去同情那些小混混跟非正义
You all come in here with your hearts bleedin' about slum kids and injustice.
你们听到他编出来的故事
You listen to some fairy tales.
完全忘了什么才是真相
You start getting through to these old ladies.
你是骗不过我的 我受够了
You're not getting through to me. I've had enough.
你们是怎么了?
What's the matter with you guys?
你们知道那孩子有罪!他应该被烧死!
You all know he's guilty! He's got to burn!
你们要让他逃过法律的制裁
He'll slip through our fingers.
-你是他的刽子手吗? -我是其中一个
- Are you his executioner? - I'm one of 'em.
你想亲自按下开关
Perhaps you'd like to pull the switch.
我的确想亲自帮那孩子行刑
For this kid, you bet I would.
我为你感到遗憾
I feel sorry for you.
只有疯子才想亲自按下电椅开关!
What it must feel like to wanna pull the switch!
你一走进这里
Ever since you walked in,
就一付想替天行道的模样
you've acted like a self-appointed public avenger.
你出自一片私心
You want to see this boy die because you want it,
想看到那孩子被判死刑
not because of the facts.
你是个虐待狂
You're a sadist.
放开我! 我要杀了他! 我要杀了他!
Let me go! I'll kill him! I'll kill him!
你该不会真的想杀了我吧?
You don't really mean you'll kill me, do you?
怎么了? 我听到吵闹声
Anything wrong? I heard some noise.
没事
No, everything's all right.
我们只是起了一点小争执
We're just... Friendly little argument.
我们已经看过了配置图
We're through with that diagram.
请你把它拿走
You can take it if you want.
拿去吧
Here you are.
你们在看什么?
What are you lookin' at?
-我想得有人站出来发言 -对不起
- Somebody has to start off again. - I beg pardon...
"对不起" 你干嘛变得那么有礼貌?
"I beg pardon." What are you so polite about?
就跟你没有礼貌的理由一样
For the same reason you're not.
我从小就是个有礼貌的人
It's the way I was brought up.
我们会来这里 不是来吵架的
That's not why we are here, to fight.
我们肩负着重责大任
We have a responsibility.
我一直觉得 这就是民主社会的优点
This, I have always thought, is a remarkable thing about democracy.
我们
That we are...
该怎么说呢? 我们被通知
What is the word? Notified.
我们收到信 被通知要来这里
That we are notified by mail to come down to this place
决定一个跟我们素昧平生的人
to decide on the guilt or innocence of a man we...
到底有没有罪
we have never heard of before.
不论做出什么样的判决
We have nothing to gain or lose
我们都拿不到好处 也没有损失
by...by our verdict.
那就是我们的国家能这么强大的原因
This is one of the reasons why we are strong.
我们不应该把这件事 跟私人的感觉扯上关系
We should not make it a... personal thing.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果没有人想发言 我有个主意
If nobody else has an idea, I might have a cutie here.
现在把事情摊在阳光下
Let's throw it out
看看我们能不能得到结论
and see if the cat licks it up.
-得到结论? -没错
- The cat licks it up? - Yeah.
外面的天色非常暗
Look how dark it's gettin' out there.
我猜应该是要下大雨了
I bet we're gonna have a storm now.
天啊 真的好热
Boy, oh boy. It's really hot, huh?
对不起 你从来都不流汗吗?
Pardon me, but...don't you ever sweat?
我不流汗的
No, I don't.
听着 我在想
Listen. I...I was wonderin' if...
或许我们该再投一次票
Maybe...maybe we should take another vote.
太棒了
Great.
或许我们接下来
Maybe we can follow this one up
该跳个舞吃点东西来庆祝一下!
with a little dancing and refreshments!
-团长先生? -我没有意见
- Mr.Foreman? - Well, that's OK with me.
有人反对进行投票吗?
Anyone doesn't wanna vote?
-来吧 -什么? 对不起
- Hey, come on. - What? Sorry.
我们应该做公开投票
I think we ought to have an open ballot.
表明自己的意愿
Call out our votes, you know?
来看看每个人的立场是什么
Let's see who stands where.
我觉得听起来挺公平的
Well, that sounds fair to me.
有人反对吗?
Anyone object?
好吧 我会照编号来叫大家 一号?
OK. I'll call off your jury numbers. One?
我是一号 我投有罪 二号?
Oh, that's me. I vote guilty. Two?
无罪
Not guilty.
三号?
Number three?
有罪
Guilty.
四号?
Number four?
有罪
Guilty.
五号?
Number five?
无罪
Not guilty.
六号?
Number six?
无罪
Not guilty.
七号?
Number seven?
有罪
Guilty.
八号?
Number eight?
无罪
Not guilty.
九号?
Number nine?
无罪
Not guilty.
十号?
Number ten?
有罪
Guilty.
十一号?
Number eleven?
无罪
Not guilty.
十二号?
Number twelve?
十二号!
Number twelve!
有罪
Guilty.
现在的票数是六比六
The vote is now six to six.
没错 我们现在要打延长赛了 对吧?
And we go into extra innings here, eh?
六比六!
Six to six!
你们之中有些人一定是疯了
I'm telling you, some of you people in here must be out of your minds.
像他那样的孩子没救了!
A kid like that!
我觉得他是什么样的孩子跟这件事无关
I don't think the kind of boy he is has anything to do with it.
事实可以决定一切
Facts determine the case.
少拿那一套来唬我!
Don't give me that!
我厌倦了事实
I'm sick and tired of facts.
反正到最后你也会扭曲一切
You can twist 'em any way you like.
那就是这个先生所强调的重点
That's exactly the point this gentleman has been making.
你一直扯着嗓门对我们大吼大叫的
You keep shouting at the top of your lungs
真希望我能年轻个几岁
I'd like to be a few years younger.
那家伙害得我
That man gets on my...
-真的好热喔 -你要喝点水吗?
- My, it's hot in here. - Want a drink of water?
不用了 谢谢你
No, no. Thanks. Thanks.
快下雨了
It's gonna rain.
你怎么知道呢? 大天才
Well, how'd you figure that out, killer?
你为什么会改变心意?
How come you changed your vote?
这个案子看起来真的有值得质疑的地方
It just seemed there was room for doubt.
你根本就是墙头草
You haven't got a leg to stand on.
我不那么认为
I don't feel that way.
很多的细节并没有查清楚
A lot of details never came out.
祝你好运
Yeah, well, good luck.
少来了 你跟其他人一样
Come on. You're like everybody else.
你想的太多反而被弄迷糊了
You think too much, you get mixed up.
你了解我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
我不认为你有权利
I don't think you have any right to...
大嘴巴
Loudmouth.
看看这场大雨
Look at that come down, will ya?
你知道吗?
You know,
这让我想起之前遇到的一场西北雨
this reminds me of a storm we had last...
那是十一月的事吗? 我不知道 可能是吧
Was it November? I don't know. Something.
那场雨下的真大
It was quite a storm we had.
当时球赛进行到一半
It was right in the middle of a game.
我们以六比七落后
We were behind -seven to six.
那时由我们来进攻
We'd just started to move the ball, made a tackle.
做出了一个漂亮的擒抱
It was gonna cut right in, slash through,
开始切往右边 一路往前冲
slashed right in, cut right through...
队上有个孩子姓史拉特利
We had this kid-Slattery.
他就跟一头蛮牛一样
He was an ox. A real ox.
我巴不得能找到另一个跟他一模一样的球员
I wish I had another one just like him.
忘了告诉你
I forgot to tell you.
我是安德鲁麦柯克高中足球的助理总教练
I'm the assistant head coach at Andrew J McCorkle High School.
那所学校在皇后区
That's out in Queens.
总之我们的攻势 非常地顺利
And anyway... we're starting to move along real nice.
你知道的 对手的防守阵线开始崩溃
You know, their whole line is just... just comin' apart.
突然间天空开始下起大雨
And it starts to come down,
雨势就跟这场雨一样大
cats and dogs, just like this.
那场雨来的很突然
Just... whoosh! You know, right down.
那真是要人命 你知道吗?
Well, it was murder, you know?
我发誓那时我差点要疯了
I swear, I...I nearly bawled.
你真的是一点办法都没有
Just... We couldn't go nowhere.
这个电扇到底是怎么一回事? 怎么会
Hey, what is it with this fan here? How come...
原来是要从电灯的开关来启动它
Must have been on the same switch with the lights.
局势开始好转了 对吧?
Well, things are lookin' up here, huh?
没错
Yeah.
天啊 凉快多了
Boy, that's better.
进了
Hey! Two points.
你们去过花园广场吗?
You guys ever go to the Garden?
那么做真的是太蠢了
That's a damn stupid thing to do.
对不起 我
Oh, I'm sorry. I...
你知道吗?
You know?
对不起
Pardon me.
你觉得如何呢? 现在是平分
Well, how do you like it? Even-steven.
令人跌破眼镜吧?
Pretty surprising, isn't it?
没错
Yes.
那个叫什么来着的高个儿
That...business before, when that tall guy, what's his name
想要引我上钩时 但那无法证明任何事
was tryin' to bait me? That doesn't prove anything.
他为什么要说我想替天行道
Where does he come off
还骂我虐待狂?
calling me a public avenger, a sadist?
谁敢不顺他的心就会被他狠狠地修理一顿
Anyone in his right mind would blow his stack.
他只是想引我上钩
He was just tryin' to bait me.
他做的太好了
He did an excellent job.
我得告诉你我们无法做出结论
I think we're going nowhere here.
我准备宣布本案将成为悬判
I'm ready to walk into court and declare a hung jury.
我们无法再继续谈下去
There's no point in this thing going on.
我赞成你的说法
I go for that, too.
把那个孩子交给下一批陪审员来处理
Let the kid take his chance with 12 other guys.
我不认为法官会接受悬判的判决
The judge won't accept a hung jury.
我们在这呆了很久了
We haven't been here long.
-我们走着瞧吧 -我不打算那么做
- Well, let's find out. - I am not in favour of that.
把本案交给下一批陪审员 那孩子是死路一条
This kid wouldn't stand a chance with another jury, and you know it.
我们无法做出结论 没有人能改变那家伙的决定
Come on, we're hung. Nobody's gonna change his vote.
-你还是觉得这个案子很合理? -没错
- Still no room for reasonable doubt? - No.
对不起
Pardon.
或许你不了解"合理怀疑"的意思
Maybe you don't fully understand the term "reasonable doubt".
你说我不了解是什么意思?
What do you mean, I don't understand?
你对这家伙有什么看法
How do you like this guy?
他们全都是一个样子
I'm tellin' you, they're all alike.
他们来到这里他们椅子都还没有坐热
They come over here and before they can take a breath
就急着告诉我们该怎么做出判决
they're telling us how to run the show.
这个家伙真的是太傲慢了
Boy, the arrogance of this guy!
好吧 请大家暂时停止争执
All right. Let's stop the arguing for about two minutes in here.
谁想发表有建设性的意见?
Now, who's got something constructive to say?
如果大家不介意的话 我有一些话想说
I'd like to go over something, if you gentlemen don't mind.
对检方来说有一件事非常重要
An important point for the prosecution
那个孩子说
was the fact that after the boy claimed...
案发时他人在电影院里
he was at the movies when the killing took place...
他不记得那部电影及片中演员的名字
he couldn't remember the names of the movies or who starred in them.
这位先生提到了重点
This gentleman has made that point.
没错 那是被告提出的唯一不在场证明
That's correct. It's the only alibi the boy offered
但他无法说明所有的细节
and he couldn't back it up with any details.
你站在那男孩的处境想想
In the boy's place
你觉得被自己的父亲打了巴掌后
do you think you could remember details...
你可以记得起这些小事吗?
after an upsetting experience such as being slapped by your father?
我想应该可以 只要这些细节很特别
I think so, if there were any special details to remember.
那孩子什么都记不起来
The boy couldn't remember the movies
因为他根本不在电影院里
because he wasn't there.
警方在那孩子家里的厨房讯问他
According to the police testimony, the boy was questioned in the kitchen
当时他父亲的尸体还躺在地上
while the body of his father was lying in the bedroom.
-在那种情况下你还想起任何事吗? -我能
- Do you think you could remember details? - I do.
在那么大的压力下?
Under great emotional stress?
一点都没错
Under great emotional stress.
他在法庭上想起所有细节说出电影跟演员的名字
He remembered them correctly in court.
对 他的律师花了一番力气才让他说出来
Yes. His lawyer took great pains to bring that out.
从案发到接受审判
He had three months to the day
他有好几个月的时间回想细节
of the trial in which to memorise them.
要查出某家电影院
It's not difficult for a lawyer to find out
当时在放映那部电影并不难
what played on a particular night.
我相信那个孩子在案发后
I'll take the testimony from right after the murder...
记不起电影名字的证词
when he couldn't remember a thing about the movies,
不论他当时是否承受极大的压力
great emotional stress or not.
-我想问你一个问题 -请说
- I'd like to ask you a personal question. - Go ahead.
-昨天晚上你在哪里? -我在家里
- Where were you last night? - I was home all night.
-前天晚上呢? -这是什么意思?
- How about the night before that? - What is this?
没关系 我不在意
It's all right.
我八点半下班然后就回家了
I left the office at 8.30 and went straight home and to bed.
大前天晚上呢?
And the night before that?
那是星期二晚上
That was...Tuesday night.
那天我去打桥牌了
The bridge tournament. I played bridge.
星期一晚上呢?
Monday night?
回想到1954年的新年除夕时 再来叫我
When you get to New Year's Eve 1954, let me know.
星期一晚上吗?
Monday night?
星期一晚上 我跟我太太去看电影
Monday night... my wife and I went to the movies.
你们看了哪部电影
What did you see?
红字环路 一部推理片
The Scarlet Circle. A whodunit.
-第二部是什么呢? -是
- What was the second feature? - The...
我待会再告诉你
I'll tell you in a minute.
杰出的什么来着
The Remarkable Mrs...Something.
杰出的布里奇夫人
The Remarkable Mrs.Bainbridge
我看过那部电影 它叫做杰出的布里奇夫人
I saw that. It's called The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge.
没错 了不起的布里奇夫人?
Yes. The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge?
主角是谁呢?
Who was in The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge?
芭芭拉隆格
Barbara...Long,
我觉得她是个漂亮的黑美人
I think it was a dark, very pretty girl.
她应该是姓林德或隆格
Ling or...Long. Something like that.
-还有谁呢? -我从来没有听过他们的名字
- Who else? - I'd never heard of them before.
它是一部低成本的二线电影 名不见经传
It was a very inexpensive second feature, with unknown...
当时你并没有承受极大的情绪压力吧?
And you weren't under an emotional stress, were you?
没有
No. I wasn't.
我想重点大家都了解了
I think the point is made.
好大的重点喔
Big point.
你爱怎么说随便你
You can talk till your tongue is draggin' on the floor.
那孩子还是有罪
The boy is guilty.
你了解我的意思吗?
Know what I mean, my friend?
-你还有喉糖吗? -已经吃完了
- You got those cough drops? - They're all gone, my friend.
天啊 雨下的还真大
Oh, boy. Look at that rain.
看来你的球赛应该会取消
There goes your ball game.
这只是一场阵雨
It's only a shower.
而且内野一定会盖上防水布
Besides, they got the infield covered.
我能再看看那把刀子吗?
Say, could I see that knife a second, please?
现在票数还是六比六平手
Well, we're still tied up six to six.
有人有任何建议吗?
Who's got a suggestion?
已经过了六点 去吃晚餐吧
It's 5 after 6. Let's get some dinner.
等到七点再说 再谈一小时吧
Why don't we wait till 7 o'clock?
我没有意见
OK with me.
我有一件事想说
There's something I'd like to say.
这件事一直让我觉得很困扰
It's been bothering me a little,
既然我们被困在这里
and as long as we're stuck...
对于死者的致命伤跟其成因
There was this whole business about the stab wound
我一直觉得不太对劲
and how it was made.
伤口的角度向下
The downward angle of it, you know?
你们又来了
Don't start with that again.
律师们已经讨论过这一点
They've been over it and over it.
我知道 但我就是觉得不对劲
I know, but I don't go along with it.
那孩子五尺七寸高
The boy was five feet seven inches tall.
他父亲是六尺二寸高
His father was six two.
他们的身高相差七寸
That's a difference of seven inches.
要往下刺伤一个比你高半尺的人
It's very awkward to stab down
不是一件很简单的事
into the chest of someone over half a foot taller.
请把刀子递给我
Give me that.
我来示范给你们看 麻烦哪位过来一下
I'll give you a demonstration. Somebody get up.
大家仔细看着 我不会再示范第二次
Watch this, I don't wanna have to do it again.
我会往下蹲让自己比他矮上七寸 好吗?
I'll make myself about six or seven inches shorter.
大概是这样 还要再低一点
That's about right. Maybe a little more.
好了 再蹲低一点
OK, a little more.
别担心我不会来真的
Now...nobody's hurt.
-是吗? -没有人会受伤的
- Right? - Right. Nobody hurt.
我就是这样刺伤比我高的人
Now, this is the way I'd stab a man who was...taller than I was.
你们看看这个角度是往下压的
Look at the angle. Down and in.
他就是这样杀了他父亲
And this is the way it was done.
你们可以说我错了
Now tell me I'm wrong.
角度往下压 一定不会错的
Down and in. There's no argument.
请等一下
Hold on a minute.
麻烦你把刀子递给我
Will you give me that?
天啊 我恨透这些事了
Boy, I hate these things.
-你看过别人互砍的样子吗? -没有
- Did you ever see a knife fight? - No.
-你呢? -没有
- You? - No.
有人看过别人互砍的样子吗?
Anybody here ever see a knife fight?
我看过
Well, I have.
当时我曲着身体
You know, on my back stoop,
他们在对街的院子里械斗
the lot across the street, back yard.
在我住的社区里拥有折叠刀不是稀奇的事
Switchblades came with the neighbourhood.
我不想去想起这种事
Funny I never thought of it before.
一直都努力地想忘了它
I guess you try to forget.
你都是怎么使用折叠刀的?
How do you use a switchblade?
没有人会这样使用折叠刀
Well, you'd never use it like this.
这样子要亮出刀子 会浪费掉太多时间
See, you'd lose too much time switching hands.
大家都是这样向下拿着刀子
Here's how. Underhand.
使用折叠刀的人都是这样拿刀子的
Anyone who's ever used one wouldn't handle it any other way.
-你确定? -我非常确定
- Are you sure? - I'm sure.
那样子才能把刀子弹开
It's why they're made to open like that.
那孩子对使用刀子非常熟悉
The boy was pretty handy with a knife.
你觉得他有办法那样杀死他父亲吗?
You think he could have made the wound that killed his father?
不可能 除非经过练习
No. Not with the experience
不然他不可能是那样拿刀子的
he got all his life handling these things.
他一定是偷偷地攻击他的
I feel he'd have gone for him underhand.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
你当时也在现场吗?
Were you there when he was killed?
不 当时现场没有其他人
No. Neither was anybody else.
你凭什么告诉我们这些凭空杜撰的事?
What are you giving us this mumbo jumbo for?
我不认为你可以判定那孩子是怎么杀人的
I don't think you can tell what wound he might have made...
因为他知道如何使用刀子
simply because he knew how to handle a knife.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
-我不知道 -你是什么意思?
- I don't know. - What do you mean, you don't know?
我不知道
I don't know.
你呢?
How about you?
我不知道其他人是怎么想的
I don't know about the rest of 'em,
但我已经厌倦了这种情况
but I'm gettin' tired of this yakety-yakkin'.
这样子下去是不会有结论的
It's gettin' us nowhere.
我想我要做出突破
So I guess I'll have to break it up.
我要改变决定投无罪一票
I'm changin' my vote to not guilty.
-你说什么? -你都听到了 我受够了
- You're what? - You heard me. I've had enough.
什么? 那不是答案
You've had enough? That's no answer.
听着 你只要搞定你自己就好了 你知道吗?
Listen, you just take care of yourself. You know?
他说的对 那不是答案
He's right. That's not an answer.
你到底是什么样的人?
What kind of a man are you?
你刚刚还投有罪一票赞同其他人的意见
You have sat here and voted guilty with everyone else
只因为你急着要去看球赛
because there are some baseball tickets burning a hole in your pocket.
现在你改变了心意
Now you have changed your vote
因为你厌倦了这些讨论
because you say you're sick of all the talking?
听我说 兄弟
Now, listen, buddy.
谁告诉你你有权
Who tells you that you have the right
这样子玩弄别人的生命?
to play like this with a man's life?
-你不在乎吗? -等一下
- Don't you care? - Now, wait a minute.
你不能那样子跟我说话
You can't talk like that to me.
我当然可以那样子跟你说话
I can talk like that to you.
如果你要投无罪一票
If you want to vote not guilty,
必须是因为你相信
do it because you are convinced...
被告的确是无罪的 而不是因为你觉得厌烦
he is not guilty, not because you've had enough.
如果你觉得他有罪 你得坚持下去
And if you think he is guilty, then vote that way.
难道你没有种去做你认为是对的事吗?
Or don't you have the guts to do what you think is right?
-听我说 -你认为他有罪还是无罪?
- Now, listen... - Guilty or not guilty?
-我说过了他无罪 -为什么?
- I told you. Not guilty. - Why?
听着 我不必
Look, I don't have to...
你非说出来不可 为什么?
You do have to. Say it. Why?
好吧 我不认为他有罪
I...I don't think he's guilty.
我要求再投一次票
I want another vote.
好的 有人要求再投一次票
OK, that's another vote called for.
最快的方法是举手 有人反对吗?
I guess the quickest way is a show of hands. Anyone object?
好吧 认为被告无罪的人 请举手
OK, all those voting not guilty, raise your hands.
一 二 三 四 五 六 七
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
八
eight.
九
Nine.
认为被告有罪的人 请举手
All those voting guilty, raise your hands.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
票数是九比三 无罪的一方占优势
Well, the vote's nine to three in favour of acquittal.
我搞不清楚你们这些人!
I don't understand you people!
你们提出的那些细节
All these picky little points you keep bringing up,
根本一点都不重要!
they don't mean nothing!
你们跟我都看到了那个孩子
You saw this kid just like I did.
你们相信 他说他的刀子不见了
Don't tell me you believe that phoney story about losing the knife
案发时他在看电影的说词
and about being at the movies.
这些人在说谎 那是他们天生的劣根性
Look, you know how these people lie. It's born in them.
不必我来提醒你们
I don't have to tell you.
他们根本不知道什么是事实!
They don't know what the truth is!
那些人杀人是不必有理由的
And they don't need any real big reason to kill someone, either.
他们喝醉了 他们全都烂醉如泥
No, sir. They get drunk. They're real big drinkers, all of 'em.
突然间有人倒在水沟里
Someone's lying in the gutter.
没有人怪他们
Nobody's blaming 'em.
那就是他们天生的劣根性
That's the way they are by nature.
你们懂吗? 他们有暴力倾向
You know what I mean? Violent.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
他们的想法跟我们一样人命是不值钱的
Human life don't mean as much to them as it does to us.
他们老是打成一团
They're lushing it up and fighting all the time,
就算有人死了!
and if somebody gets killed, somebody gets killed!
他们也不在乎!
They don't care!
他们之间还是有好人
Sure, there's some good things about 'em, too.
我是第一个会那么说的人
I'm the first one to say that.
我认识一两个还不错的混混 但那是例外
I've known a couple who were OK, but that's the exception.
大部份的人都很无情!
Most of 'em, it's like they have no feelings!
他们什么事都做得出来!
They can do anything!
这是怎么一回事?
What's going on here?
我试着告诉你们
I'm trying to tell you.
你们犯了大错 那孩子是骗子
You're making a big mistake, you people.
我知道 我太了解那些人了
This kid is a liar. I know it. I know all about them.
听我说 他们都是大坏蛋
Listen to me. They're no good.
他们之中根本没有好人
There's not a one of 'em who's any good.
这到底是怎么一回事?
What's going on here?
我说出我的想法 你们
I speak my piece, and you...
听我说
Listen to me.
被告是个小混混
This kid on trial here. His type.
难道你们不了解他们那种人吗?
Well, don't you know about them?
他们是危险人物
There's a... There's a danger here.
这些人很危险
These people are dangerous.
他们真疯狂
They're... wild.
听我说
Listen to me.
-听着 -我在听
- Listen to me. - I have.
请你坐下把你的嘴巴闭上
Now, sit down and don't open your mouth again.
有时候我告诉你
Some of the time...I tell you.
面对这种事
It's always difficult
要排除个人的偏见真的很难
to keep personal prejudice out of a thing like this.
不论去到哪里
Wherever you run into it,
偏见总是遮蔽了真相
prejudice always obscures the truth.
我真的不知道真相是什么
I don't really know what the truth is.
我想应该没有任何人知道真相是什么
I don't suppose anybody will ever really know.
我们九个人现在觉得被告是无辜的
Nine of us now seem to feel that the defendant is innocent.
但我们是在赌一个可能性
But we're just gambling on probabilities.
或许我们错了
We may be wrong.
我们或许会放走一个杀人犯 我不知道
We may be trying to let a guilty man go free. I don't know.
没有人知道 但我们有合理的怀疑
Nobody really can. But we have a reasonable doubt.
那是我们的司法制度中非常珍贵的一部份
And that's something that's very valuable in our system.
除非十分确定
No jury can declare a man guilty
陪审团无法判决被告有罪
unless it's sure.
我们九个人不了解
We nine can't understand
你们三个为什么还那么地确定
how you three are still so sure.
-或是你们可以好好解释一下 -我会的
- Maybe you can tell us. - I'll try.
有说地方你的确很有说服力
You've made some excellent points,
但我相信那孩子有罪
but I still believe the boy is guilty.
原因有二
I have two reasons.
一是目赌凶案经过的那位女士
One: The evidence given by the woman across the street,
在法庭上做出的证词
who actually saw the murder committed.
那是最重要的证词
That's the most important testimony.
二是她描述她看到的凶案经过
And two: The fact that she described the stabbing
她说她看到那个孩子
by saying she saw the boy
双手高举过头拿刀往他父亲的胸口刺下
raise his arm over his head and stab down into the father's chest.
她看到他杀了人
She saw him do it, the wrong way.
一点都没错
That's absolutely right.
我们来谈谈这位女士
Let's talk about this woman for a moment.
她说案发当晚她大约在十一点上床睡觉
She said she went to bed about eleven o'clock that night.
她的床就在窗户旁边 只要她一往外看
Her bed was next to the window, and she could look out
她可以看到那孩子在对街的房间
and see directly into the boy's room across the street.
那晚她翻来覆去大约一个小时
She tossed and turned for over an hour.
大约在十二点十分她转身面向窗户
Finally, she turned toward the window at about 10 minutes after 12,
她往外一看
and as she looked out
透过电车车窗看到杀人的经过
she saw the killing through the windows of a passing el train.
她说在凶案发生后四周是一片漆黑
She said the lights went out after the killing
但她非常清楚地看到那孩子
but that she got a good look at the boy
拿刀刺向他父亲
in the act of stabbing his father.
在我的看法里 这项证词坚不可破
As far as I can see it, this is unshakeable testimony.
就是那么一回事
Well, that's the whole case.
你有什么看法?
What do you think?
你觉得呢?
How about you?
我不知道
I don't know.
很多证词都有待调查
So much evidence to sift.
这是一个很复杂的案子
This is a pretty complicated business.
老实说我不明白你们为什么会认为他无罪
Frankly, I don't see how you can vote for acquittal.
要安排这样的证词并不容易
It's not so easy to arrange the evidence.
抛开其他的证据不谈!
Throw out all the other evidence!
那位女士真的看到他了!
The woman saw him do it!
你还要什么样的证据呢?
What else do you want?
-或许 -我们来投票吧
- Well, maybe... - Let's vote on it.
好吧 有人要求再度投票 有人反对吗?
OK, there's another vote called for. Anyone object?
好吧 我改变了心意 他有罪
All right. I'm changing my vote. He's guilty.
其他人呢? 现在票数是八比四
Anybody else? The vote is eight to four.
为什么你那么得意呢? 那只是一票
Why is this such a personal triumph for you, this one vote?
我说过此案会形成悬判 这样子告诉法官吧
OK. I say we're a hung jury. I say we take it in to the judge.
你们觉得如何呢? 我想听听大家的意见
How about it? I wanna hear arguments.
这都是你惹出来的 你觉得如何呢?
You, you're the leader of the cause. What about it?
我们再来讨论一次
Let's go over it again.
我们已经讨论过了
We've been over it again.
那孩子像球一样
The boy in the grey flannel suit
被我们踢来踢去
is bouncin' back and forth like a tennis ball.
我们不该再折磨他了
There's no point in getting nasty.
你只是想为自己争一口气
You keep trying to turn this into a contest.
好吧
OK.
或许我们该应该订出一个最后期限
Maybe we can talk about setting some kind of time limit.
时间一到我们就得做出结论
Yeah. Once around for the deal, huh?
现在是六点十五分
It's... a quarter after six.
之前有人提过七点要吃晚餐
Someone before mentioned seven o'clock.
我们就讨论到七点
That's a point at which we might begin to discuss
不论这个案子会不会形成悬判
whether we're a hung jury or not.
你不舒服吗?
Don't you feel well?
我很好 谢谢你
I feel perfectly well, thank you.
我觉得讨论到七点是个合理的
I was saying seven o'clock would be a reasonable time...
我会那么说是因为
The reason I asked that was because
你一直在按摩你的鼻子
you were rubbing your nose like...
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry for interrupting.
你的动作让我想起了一件事
But you made a gesture that reminded me of something.
我正在说服大家订出规则来
I'm trying to settle something here.
我觉得这件事非常重要
Well, I think this is important.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我相信 你会原谅我这么说
Now, then. I'm sure you'll pardon me for this
我一直在想你为什么要那样按摩你的鼻子
but I was wondering why you rub your nose like that.
少来了
Come on, will you?
我是在跟
At this point I happen to be talking to the gentleman
坐在你隔壁的先生说话
sitting next to you.
你为什么要那样按摩你的鼻子?
Now, why were you rubbing your nose like that?
我会这么做
If it's any of your business,
是因为我觉得鼻子很痛
I was rubbing it because it bothers me a little.
对不起 那是因为你戴眼镜的关系吗?
Oh, I'm sorry. Is it...is it because of your eyeglasses?
没错 我们可以谈正事了吗?
It is. Now could we get on to something else?
你的眼镜在鼻梁侧面
Your eyeglasses made those two deep impressions
压出那些很深的印子
on the sides of your nose.
我之前没有注意到
I hadn't noticed that before.
那应该会很痛
That must be annoying.
你说的对
It is very annoying.
我不了解那种感觉
I wouldn't know about that.
我的视力很好没有戴过眼镜
I've never worn eyeglasses.
请你别谈这些眼科医生才会关心的事好吗?
Listen, will you come on already with the optometrist bit?
出庭作证 说她看到凶案经过的那位女士
The woman who testified that she saw the killing
鼻梁侧面也有相同的印子
had those same marks on the sides of her nose.
-天啊! 他说的对 -请安静
- Holy smoke! He's right. - Please.
再给我一点时间 让我把话说完
Just give me a minute...and I'll be finished.
我不知道其他人是否注意到
I don't know if anyone else noticed that about her.
那时我并不在意
I didn't think of it then,
但我的脑海中一直浮现她的脸庞
but I've been going over her face...in my mind.
她脸上也有这样的印子
She had those same marks.
她在法庭上也一直在按摩鼻子
She kept rubbing them in court.
他说的对 她的确常常那么做
He's right. She did do that a lot.
这位女士大约是四十五岁
This woman was about 45 years old.
她很努力让自己看起来
She was making a tremendous effort to look 35.
只有三十五岁的样子
For her first public appearance.
她化了浓妆 染了头发
Heavy make-up. Dyed hair.
穿上年轻女孩才会穿的新衣服
Brand-new clothes that should have been worn by a younger woman.
她没有戴眼镜 女人常那么做
No glasses. Well, women do that.
你们应该能了解她们的心态
See if you can get a mental picture of her.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean, no glasses?
你怎么知道她有戴眼镜?
How do you know whether she wore glasses?
就因为她会按摩鼻子吗?
Just cos she was rubbin' her nose?
她脸上也有那种印子
She had those marks. I saw 'em.
你觉得那代表什么意思?
So? What do you think that means?
我厌倦了你总是大吼大叫
I'm sick of your yellin'...
好了 别激动
Come on. Forget it.
听着 他说的对
Hey, listen. Listen, he's right.
我也看到了 我是最靠近她的人
I saw them too. I was the closest one to her.
她鼻子上也有那些印子
She had these things on the side of her nose.
这是叫什么来着的?
What point are you makin'?
她染了头发 鼻子上有印子
She had dyed hair, marks on her nose.
你想要证明什么?
What does that mean?
这些印子可能是
Could those marks be made by
除了眼镜以外的其他东西造成的吗?
anything other than eyeglasses?
不可能
No. They couldn't.
我没看到她鼻子上有印子
I didn't see any marks!
我看到了
I did.
奇怪的是 我之前没有想到这一点
Strange, but I didn't think about it before.
律师呢? 他为什么没有提出质疑?
What about the lawyer? Why didn't the lawyer say something?
这个房间里有十二个人
There are twelve people in here concentrating on this case.
有十一个人也没有想到这一点
Eleven of us didn't think of it either.
检察官呢?
What about the district attorney?
你觉得是他要她
You think he'd pull that?
在出庭时拿下眼镜吗?
Have her testify without her glasses?
有些女人不喜欢戴眼镜
Ever see a woman who didn't want to wear them
因为戴上眼镜她们会变得很丑
because they spoil her looks?
好吧 她的鼻子上有印子
OK. She had marks on her nose.
我承认这一点
I'm givin' you that.
那是眼镜造成的 对吧?
From glasses, right?
她不想戴上眼镜
She didn't wanna wear 'em out of the house
那样子大家会觉得她很漂亮
so people'd think she's gorgeous.
但她看到那孩子杀死他父亲时
But when she saw this kid killin' his father,
她是一个人待在房里
she was in the house alone.
就是那样
That's all.
你会戴着眼镜睡觉吗?
Do you wear glasses when you go to bed?
我不会那么做
No. I don't.
没有人会戴着眼镜睡觉
No one wears eyeglasses to bed.
所以我们可能合理地推论
It's logical to assume that
她躺在床上时并没有戴眼镜
she wasn't wearing them in bed.
-你怎么知道? -那是我的推论
- How do you know? - I don't know. I'm guessing.
我推论她往窗外看去时
I'm also guessing that she didn't put them on
并没有戴眼镜
when she looked out of the window.
她作证说 案发时她刚好往窗外看去
She testified the killing took place just as she looked out.
灯是关着的 她根本没有时间把眼镜戴上
The lights went off. She didn't have time to put them on.
还有另一个推论
Here's another guess.
她真的认为她看到了那个孩子
She honestly thought she saw the boy kill his father.
但我觉得她只看到模糊的影子
I say she only saw a blur.
你怎么知道她看到了什么?
How do you know what she saw?
他怎么会知道那么多事?
How does he know all that?
你怎么知道她戴的是哪一种眼镜?
How do you know what glasses she wore?
可能是太阳镜! 或许她得的是远视!
Maybe they were sunglasses! Maybe she was far-sighted!
你怎么会知道?
What do you know?
那个女人的视力现在成了争议
I only know the woman's eyesight is in question now.
她得在昏暗的夜色中不戴眼镜
She had to be able to identify a person 60 feet away,
辨识出六十尺外的人
at night, without glasses.
只靠这样的证据你不能让一个人坐上电椅
You can't send someone off to die on evidence like that.
少来这一套
Aw, don't give me that.
-你觉得她看错了吗? -不
- Might she not have made a mistake? - No.
-那是不可能的吗? -那是不可能的
- It's not possible? - No, it's not possible.
这可能吗?
Is it possible?
他是无罪的
Not guilty.
你觉得他有罪吗?
Do you think he's guilty?
我觉得他有罪
I think he's guilty.
你呢?
Do you?
他无罪
No.
我被说服了 他无罪
I'm convinced. Not guilty.
你是怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
我现在有了合理的怀疑
I have a reasonable doubt now.
现在是十一比一
It's eleven to one.
其他的证据又是怎么一回事?
What about all the other evidence?
那把凶刀跟其他的证据呢?
What about all that stuff? The...the knife? The whole business?
你说过我们可以抛开其他的证据
Well, you said we could throw out all the other evidence.
我们现在该怎么办?
Well, what do we do now?
你只剩下一个人
You're alone.
我不在乎自己是不是孤军奋战
I don't care whether I'm alone or not.
这是我的权利
It's my right.
这是你的权利
It's your right.
你们打算怎么办? 我认为他有罪
Well, what do you want? I say he's guilty.
我们要听听你的说法
We want to hear your arguments.
我该说的都说了
I gave you my arguments.
我们不相信你的说法 我们想再听一次
We're not convinced. We want to hear them again.
我们有的是时间
We have as much time as it takes.
所有的证据
Everything-every single thing
在法庭上做出的所有证词都证明他有罪
that took place in that courtroom says he's guilty.
难道你们认为我是白痴吗?
What do you think? I'm an idiot or somethin'?
你们为什么不相信
Take that stuff about the old man
住在楼下的老人听到了声音!
who lived there and heard everything!
你们推翻了凶刀的理论
Or this business about the knife.
就因为我们找到了类似的刀子?
They found another one exactly like it?
那个老人看到他 从楼上冲了下来
The old man saw him! Right there, on the stairs.
他到底花了几秒跑到门口那有什么差别?
What's the difference how many seconds it was?
所有的证据
Every single thing.
刀子从他口袋的破洞掉了出去
The knife fallin' through a hole in his pocket.
你不能证明他没有夺门而出!
You can't prove he didn't get to the door!
你可以量时间
Sure, you can take all the time,
蹒跚地走来走去 但你无法证明那一点!
hobble around the room, but you can't prove it!
关于电车 跟电影院又是怎么一回事呢?
And what about this business of the el? And the movies?
我非常确定那都是他编出来的谎言
There's a phoney deal if I ever heard one.
我跟你赌五千块 我可以记得我看过的电影
I'll bet you $5,000 I'd remember the movies I saw.
我告诉你们
I'm tellin' you,
所有的事实都遭到了扭曲!
everything that's gone on has been twisted and turned!
关于眼镜的理论
This business with the glasses?
你怎么知道当时她没有戴眼镜?
How do you know she didn't have 'em on?
这位女士在法庭上作证!
This woman testified in open court!
还有那孩子的喊叫声呢?
And what about hearin' the kid yell?
我告诉你们 我知道什么才是事实
I'm tellin' ya, I've got all the facts here.
好了
Well
够了 这就是事实
that's it. That's the whole case.
你们觉得呢?
Well?
快说啊!
Say something!
你们是一群狠心的混蛋
You lousy bunch of bleedin' hearts.
你们无法威胁我
You're not gonna intimidate me.
我要坚持我的想法
I'm entitled to my opinion.
该死的孩子 你毁了自己的一生!
Rotten kids... You work your life out!
不
No...
他无罪
Not guilty.
我们准备好了
We're ready now.
嘿!
Hey!
-你叫什么名字? -我是戴维斯
- What's your name? - Davis.
我叫迈卡迪
My name's McCardle.
-再见了 -再见
- Well, so long. - So long.